<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<texte>
<page num="1"><![CDATA[
Autumn-Winter 2012-2013 € 4,50 SFR 6,80 £ 3.00 $ 5.40

#19 ZURICH

Markus & Daniel Freitag
DESIGNERS

THE SWISS EDITION - FOCUS ON SUSTAINABLE ELEGANCE

 ]]></page>
<page num="2"><![CDATA[
real watches for real people

Oris Artix GT Chronograph
Automatic mechanical chronograph Stainless steel case with turning top ring Special linear display for the small second Water resistant to 100 m

www.oris.ch

 ]]></page>
<page num="3"><![CDATA[
EDITORIAL Richard Girardot

3

A COUNTRY OF CONNOISSEURS
DEAR CLUB MEMBERS,

It is no coincidence that edelweiss chooses to grow in Switzerland. This rare, delicate flower embodies this country of modest refinement, the birthplace of Nespresso. It can only be glimpsed by connoisseurs, those who appreciate natural beauty which needs no embellishment to work its charm. It is this aesthetic appreciation that can be found in Zurich, destination of choice for architects and designers alike. And it is this that attracts the great masters, such as chef Heiko Nieder, who has cast his spell over the Dolder Grand and has just been awarded a second Michelin star. The Swiss understand and admire the treasures hidden inside the smallest flower and the least imposing mountain or lake. They also know how to protect them. Switzerland is at the forefront of the recycling industry and is a model of sustainable lifestyle. This country breathes life into dead objects and makes them so beautiful that they are transformed into objects of desire, as in the case of the Freitag brothers, whose bags made from former truck tarpaulins are sought after the world over. This philosophy is shared by Nespresso, as we reuse old capsules to create stunning machine casings. Intrigued? Read on to find out about the origins of recycling in this issue. You can also discover the secrets of Hawaii Kona, the newest Special Reserve. In the capable hands of Nespresso, this jewel of a coffee from a very small island comes into its own. And there’s another surprise: U, the new modular machine which fits around you. Enjoy the magazine and your coffee.

RICHARD GIRARDOT CEO, NESTLÉ NESPRESSO S.A.

 ]]></page>
<page num="4"><![CDATA[
4

CONTRIBUTORS

Our team,
SANDRINE GIACOBETTI JÉRÔME BILIC
PHOTOGRAPHER Jérôme works with Marie Leteuré at “Elle à Table” and also photographs food for Éditions Solar publishing house.
His coffee moment:

NESPRESSO MAGAZINE IS PUBLISHED BY NESTLÉ NESPRESSSO S.A. PUBLICATION DIRECTOR Stéphane Detaille. EXECUTIVE EDITOR Lise Peneveyre. Concept/Production: LAGARDÈRE CUSTOM PUBLISHING, 124, RUE DANTON, 92300 LEVALLOIS-PERRET, FRANCE. TEL. +33 (0)1 41 34 93 63 PUBLISHER Évelyne Laquit. EXECUTIVE MANAGER Jérôme Pébereau. EDITOR-IN-CHIEF Sandrine Giacobetti. ART DIRECTOR Xavier Bouré. STUDIO MANAGER Matthieu Carré. COORDINATORS Nadine Male Hershkovitch, with Manuela Hurel. EDITORIAL SECRETARY Marie-Françoise Dufief. CONTRIBUTORS FOR THIS EDITION Alexandra Dejean, Francis Dolric, Dominique Dupuich, Stéphanie Durteste, Camille El Beze, Nadia Hamam, Anna Penotti. TRANSLATION Datawords www.datawords.com ADVERTISING MANAGEMENT Lagardère Publicité. Tel. +33 (0)1 41 34 85 53 Tel. +33 (0)1 41 34 85 47 Advertising Manager: Franck Stoeckel Client Managers: Marie-Christine Lanza, Séverine Franier PHOTOLITHO ASTO-PCS. PRINTER Mohn media Mohndruck GmbH.

OLIVIER GACHEN
PHOTOGRAPHER He has travelled the world, producing portraits and reports for French publications including “Elle”, “Libération” and “Le Monde”. He is just as passionate about his work in cinema.
His coffee moment:

JOURNALIST Sandrine is Editor-in-Chief of the French magazine “Elle à Table” and has worked on numerous cooking and lifestyle publications.
Her coffee moment:

“Always stress-free.” She waits until she’s completely relaxed and then makes herself a foaming latte macchiato.

He takes a Fortissio Lungo in the morning. “With a sprinkle of sugar, because it’s strong.”

A lungo for breakfast, a strong espresso after lunch.

This magazine is printed on paper certified by:

MARIE LETEURÉ

STYLIST Food stylist for “Elle à Table” magazine, Marie has also written a number of lifestyle and cookery books for Marabout and Solar publishing houses.
Her coffee moment:

JEAN-CLAUDE AMIEL
PHOTOGRAPHER His photographs illustrate the recipe pages and features of “Elle à Table” and other French publications.
His coffee moment:

JULIEN BOURÉ
JOURNALIST Regular reporter for the Travel and Portrait pages of “Elle à Table” magazine, and writer for the “Fooding” restaurant guide.
His coffee moment:

When she arrives at her photography studio she enjoys a Rosabaya de Colombia for its slightly acidic undertones of summer fruits.

A white Decaffeinato in the afternoon.

Throughout the day, in small but regular doses!

© Copyright 2012 Nestlé Nespresso S.A. All rights reserved. Nespresso, the names of the various Nespresso coffee varieties and the Nespresso logos mentioned in the Nespresso Magazine are trademarks of Société des Produits Nestlé S.A. that may be registered in certain countries.

 ]]></page>
<page num="5"><![CDATA[
True greatness
lies in the idea
Niessing Ring® S – small, strong, sexy. The floating diamond, held solely by the power of tension: A great idea that still fascinates after more than 30 years. Niessing Ring® S presents itself with new small dimensions, made exclusively of platinum. www.niessing.com/niessing-ring-s

 ]]></page>
<page num="6"><![CDATA[
Fibers surprises

Copyright BLI-DBP® - August 2012

Combining woven carbon and glass ﬁbers with ultra-thin stainless steel gives a very masculine look and an unmatched wearing comfort.

 ]]></page>
<page num="7"><![CDATA[
CONTENTS Autumn-Winter 2012-2013

7

P. 40

P. 22

P. 60

P. 82

P. 46

P. 52

P. 66

P. 76
3
EDITORIAL

40 46 52 60 66 72

CITIZENS OF HONOUR

86

THE EXPERTS

THE FREITAG BROTHERS

COLLECTIONS

NOW
9 10 12 18
Jean-Claude Amiel - Jérôme Bilic - Olivier Gachen.

STYLE

OUT AND ABOUT DESIGN ADDICT INTERVIEW

SWISS MADE
CHEF

NESPRESSO & VOUS
92 96 98
RECYCLING EVERLASTING

HEIKO NIEDER
DESIGN

ALUMINIUM
ECOLABORATIONTM

20

DIETER MEIER COLUMN CAFÉ RENVERSÉ SWITZERLAND’S SECRET WEAPON

THE NEW ZURICH SCENE
GOURMET COFFEE

RAINFOREST ALLIANCE
CLUB MEMBERS

SWISS SWEETS
HISTORY

PEOPLE, STYLE, TASTE
22
CITY GUIDE

LADY DADA
74 76 82
CULT OBJECT

100 NEWS NESPRESSO IN BRIEF 102 AMERICA’S CUP

CANNES FILM FESTIVAL

ZURICH CONFIDENTIAL, WITH SIX NESPRESSO CLUB MEMBERS

SWISS CHOCOLATE
GRANDS CRUS

HAWAII KONA
CYBER CAFE

MAGNETIC ATTRACTION

LUC DU BOIS, SAILING DREAM 104 SELECTION MACHINES & COLLECTIONS 106 NESPRESSO BOUTIQUES AND CLUBS INFORMATION USEFUL ADDRESSES AND ZURICH CITY GUIDE MAP

 ]]></page>
<page num="8"><![CDATA[
It’s sure, it’s
In prime locations along the left and right banks of the Seine in Paris, COGEDIM designs exceptional living spaces just for you!
PARIS 4TH ARRT. - Nouvelle Vague
Non-contractual illustrations designed to provide the overall architectural intentions, subject to modiﬁcations.

Between the Seine, the Bastille and the Marais, discover a cascade of gently curving terraces and balconies offer breathtaking views.

PARIS 7TH ARRT. - Paris 7 Rive Gauche
In the heart of the SèvresBabylone quarter, right near the Bon Marché, enjoy a series of gardens, rare amenities and reﬁned ﬁnishing touches.

cogedim.com

+33 1 60 79 86 70

 ]]></page>
<page num="9"><![CDATA[
NOW Out and about

9

WHEN IT WAS BUILT IN 1897, THE LÖWENBRÄU BREWERY WAS REGARDED AS THE MOST MODERN OF SWISS FACTORIES, WITH AN ANNUAL OUTPUT OF 60,000 HECTOLITRES. Nowadays, the

The former Löwenbräu brewery, a new destination for modern art.

LÖWENBRÄU
ART COMPLEX, ZURICH
THE
Production Dominique Dupuich
Jean-Claude Amiel

complex can pride itself on being one of the most productive modern art centres. The Löwenbräu site, to the west of Zurich, will eventually host a complex of galleries, ofﬁces and apartments nestling in amongst the old red brick warehouses. Over the last few years, inﬂuential Zurich art institutions such as the Kunsthalle museum of modern art, have

FORMER L ÖWENBRÄU BREWERY IS NOW HOME TO A GROUNDBREAKING MODERN ART MUSEUM TO QUENCH THE THIRST OF ANY ART LOVER .

moved into the renovated former brewery buildings. This year, the Kunsthalle has also built an extension to accommodate new exhibition areas and archives: a white concrete cube, balancing like a Lego block on top of the red brick rectangle. The extension was designed by Zurich architects Gigon and Guyer and Atelier WW, an inaugural exhibition in June 2012 entitled, ‘Looking Back for the Future’. When it comes to looking to the past to better understand the future, the conversion of the Löwenbräu industrial site into an urban space of the future is the perfect example. n
> Limmatstrasse 268, 8005 Zürich

 ]]></page>
<page num="10"><![CDATA[
10

NOW Design
THE MAGIC CHEST
From the Swiss peeler to the Japanese casserole dish, from the French-crafted chopping board to the Swedish mortar and pestle, 43 essential hand-crafted cooking implements are brought together in one elegant chest. Treat yourself or give one away as a wedding present, thanks to an ingenious online contribution system.
> malle W.Trousseau. www.mallewtrousseau.com

PIANISSIMO

The Piani lamp-cum-tray by Ronon & Erwan Bouroullec was named lamp of the year by Wallpaper magazine and perfectly combines business with pleasure. It is beautifully moulded from ABS plastic, can be installed anywhere and radiates a soft glow. Best of all, you can empty your pockets onto the tray: letters, phone, pencils, keys, watch, jewellery, powder compact... and why not an Espresso? We love it in white, black, red or green.
> Piani lamp. www.ﬂos.com

STANDS ON THE SHORES BUILDING DESIGNED CALLING ALL LE CORBUSIER LOVERS: THE LAST CORBUSIAN COLOURS,BY THE ARCHITECT AND WAS COMMISSIONED OPENED IN 1967, OF LAKE ZURICH. IT IS A TYPICAL STRUCTURE IN TRANSFORMED IT INTO A MUSEUM EXHIBITING THE BY HEIDI WEBER, AN ADMIRER OF THE ARCHITECT, WHO THEN C . MAKE SURE TO CATCH ‘LE CORBUSIER ET LA PHOTOGRAPHIE’ (‘LEIN ORTH MASTER’S PICTORIAL AND GRAPHIC WORKS HIS MARK THE 125 ANNIVERSARY OF HIS BIRTH BUSIER AND PHOTOGRAPHY’), A PHOTOGRAPHIC EXHIBITION TO -DE-FONDS, OPEN UNTIL JANUARY. > www.centrelecorbusier.com and www.lecorbusier2012.ch HOME TOWN OF LA CHAUX

VIVA REVIVAL

The famous unisex Cartier ‘Love’ bracelet, which is fastened around the wrist using a screwdriver, was first created in the 1970s and is now making a comeback on the slender wrists of elegant women from Zurich to Acapulco. Not seen without a large masculine steel wrist watch and a stack of fetish bracelets – Brazilian designs and other lucky charms – throughout the year.
> ‘Love’ bracelet. www.cartier.com

All rights reserved - Jean-Claude Amiel - Katel Riou © Cartier 2009.

 ]]></page>
<page num="11"><![CDATA[
Composition The arrangement of parts makes the whole – USM combines the purity of color and the strength of form.
Visit our showroom or request detailed information. USA: USM U. Schaerer Sons Inc., 28 – 30 Greene St., New York, NY 10013, Phone +1 212 371 1230 International: USM U. Schärer Söhne AG, 3110 Münsingen Switzerland, Phone +41 31 720 72 72 Showrooms: Berlin, Bern, Düsseldorf, Hamburg, New York, Paris, Tokyo info@usm.com, www.usm.com

 ]]></page>
<page num="12"><![CDATA[
12

NOW Addict

CRYSTAL BALL

Baccarat turned to the students of ECAL, the prestigious school of art and design in Lausanne, Switzerland, to divine the future of the crystal vase. Masters students from around fifteen different countries took on the role of glass-blower’s apprentice and came up with 14 variations on the theme of the vase – inspired variously by building blocks, the game of consequences, the leaning tower of Pisa, braces, the harlequin theme and more.
> Vase-O-Rama. www.baccarat.com

THERME VALS, DESIGNED BY PETER ZUMTHOR AND ONLY TWO HOURS FROM ZURICH, NEEDS NO INTRODUCTION, BUT DEVOTEES OF SPA TREATMENTS AND ARCHITECTURE SHOULD ALSO LOOK OUT FOR THE MINERALBAD SPAS, DESIGNED BY FELLOW SWISS ARCHITECT MARIO BOTTA. THE TSCHUGGEN SPA, 150 KM FROM ZURICH, AND THE RIGI KALTBAD SPA, ONLY 38 KM AWAY (PICTURED) ARE WELL WORTH A VISIT : THEY SEEM TO EMERGE FROM THE DEPTHS OF THE EARTH, FUTURISTIC YET MINIMALIST IN DESIGN. > www.tschuggen .ch and www.mineralbad-rigi-kaltbad.ch

VERY ICE HOTEL

North America’s only ice hotel has moved closer to Quebec city centre and is proving to be the new star of the winter season, from January to March. Unlike the Swedish version in the depths of Lapland, visitors can stay here for a weekend break and go walking, dancing, tobogganing, have a drink at the ice bar or even have a very white wedding in the beautifully carved chapel.
> icehotel-canada.com

BlueWaterCom.ch - Lucrousseau.com - All rights reserved.

 ]]></page>
<page num="13"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="14"><![CDATA[
14

NOW Addict

COFFEE TIME IN LONDON
DOES NESPRESSO HAVE A GOOD SENSE OF TIMING? YES, IF THE OPENING OF ITS LATEST BOUTIQUES IN LONDON IS ANYTHING TO GO BY. Just a few days before

the Olympic Games, the brand’s ﬂagship dropped anchor on Regent Street, while the Brompton Road Boutique replaced the outlet on Beauchamp Place. Just a stone’s throw from Piccadilly, the immense Regent Street Boutique has all the assets it needs to satisfy its English and international customers. Who would have thought? In the land of tea, there now stands a palace given over to the art of coffee. Indeed, the Nespresso experience has gained many enthusiasts. In the words of Brema Drohan, United Kingdom and Republic of Ireland Managing Director: “This place satisﬁes a growing passion among the British for enjoying high quality coffee.” In the

All rights reserved – Jean-Claude Amiiel

spacious boutique, Club Members are greeted and invited to taste Grands Crus, with guidance provided by Coffee Specialists. They are also given the opportunity to take advantage of the Pick-Up service which allows them to order their purchases remotely and collect them within two hours. A deposit container for used capsules is also available, along with information on Nespresso’s recycling programme. It seems the coffee culture is now in full swing. Regent Street and Brompton Road are sure to be THE places to enjoy it! n 54-62 Regent Street and 87-135 Brompton Road

 ]]></page>
<page num="15"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="16"><![CDATA[
16

NESPRESSO Magazine

NESPRESSO MAGAZINE WILL SOON BE AVAILABLE ON IPAD
AN ENHANCED VERSION OF YOUR MAGAZINE ON I P AD AND TOUCH THE BEATING HEART OF CITIES AROUND THE WORLD .

COMING SOON

DISCOVER

THE

MAGAZINE IS ALSO AVAILABLE IN AN ANIMATED AT WWW . NESPRESSO . COM / MAGAZINE .

PDF

VERSION

 ]]></page>
<page num="17"><![CDATA[
M ESURE ET D ÉMESURE *

TONDA 1950
Rose gold Ultra-thin automatic movement Hermès alligator strap Made in Switzerland www.parmigiani.ch

* EXACT AND EXULTANT

LES ATELIERS PARMIGIANI ISTANBUL, MOSCOW, BEIJING, SHANGHAI LES STUDIOS PARMIGIANI PORTO CERVO, DUBAI, MUNICH QATAR AL MAJED JEWELLERY | HONG KONG EMPEROR WATCH & JEWELLERY LONDON HARRODS | NEW YORK CELLINI | PARIS ARIJE | ROMA HAUSMANN CONDOTTI SINGAPORE THE HOUR GLASS | ZÜRICH GÜBELIN

 ]]></page>
<page num="18"><![CDATA[
T H I S B A N K E R ’ S S O N H A S N O T O N LY L E N T HIS VOCAL CHORDS TO THE ELECTRONIC M U S I C G R O U P Y E L L O : HE IS ALSO A PERFORMER, RESTAURATEUR, AND EVEN A FARMER. A MAN WHO TAKES HIS DIVERSIONS VERY SERIOUSLY.
Text Julien Bouré Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

MEIER

DIETER

 ]]></page>
<page num="19"><![CDATA[
INTERVIEW 7 Questions for…

19

1

HIS MUSICAL INSPIRATIONS

The saxophonist John Coltrane, who was canonised by the African Orthodox Church for his pure creative insanity, and Ludwig van Beethoven’s late string quartets, for their crepuscular beauty.
A SWISS OBJECT HE COULD NOT LIVE WITHOUT

4

HIS ARTISTIC IDOL

2

The luxury watches produced by ﬁne watchmakers Ulysse Nardin for over one hundred years in the tiny Frenchspeaking village of Le Locle. The village’s history as a centre of watchmaking has earned it Unesco World Heritage status.
HIS GREATEST AESTHETIC ACHIEVEMENT

Lou Reed, from his Velvet Underground days. Although unforgettable, his solo career (whose high point was the outspoken lyrics of the dark album “New York”) never transcended his time as singer and guitarist of the legendary group, which nonetheless remained in obscurity until after it disbanded in 1970. An aﬁcionado of the rock scene once claimed that even though only a few thousand fans bought their ﬁrst record (whose cover art by Andy Warhol featured a rather ambiguous banana) everyone who bought it formed a band.
ARGENTINIAN PLEASURES

His organically certiﬁed beef and vintages are bursting with character and can be found on the menus of his establishments in Zurich (Bärengasse and Atelier Bar).

6 7

HIS GUILTY PLEASURE

Golf. He is a regular at the Zumikon course in the countryside near Zurich.
HIS COFFEE

Hot on the heels of the coffee he produces (with two partners) in the Dominican Republic, which he ﬁlters like Assam tea, comes Ristretto Grand Cru. n

3
All Rights Reserved

The success of Yello, the electronic music group from German-speaking Switzerland, for which he has been the vocalist since 1978. Along with his creative partner Boris Blank, the group’s synthetic, syncretic, eccentric, cathartic style was an important inﬂuence upon the identity of the 1980s.

5

After the Argentine tango, the pure Malbec wine “Puro” that he produces sustainably near Mendoza in the famous vineyards of the Andean foothills. For nearly ﬁfteen years, Dieter Meier has lived between Zurich and his Ojo de Agua ranch, a 2,200-hectare farm located near Mar del Plata.

DIETER MEIER IN 7 DATES
1945 Born in Zurich. 1971 First artistic performances: he makes use

of 1,100 billboards, encouraging passersby to donate 10,000 francs. 1978 Joins Boris Blank as part of Yello, becoming the group’s vocalist. 1984 Directs the music video for “Big in Japan”, one of new-wave group Alphaville’s biggest hits. 1985 Release of “Stella”, Yello’s fourth album, whose track “Oh Yeah” has enjoyed lasting success. 1997 Buys a 2,200-hectare farm in Argentina, and starts organic agriculture. 2008 His first restaurant, Bärengasse, opens in Zurich, four years before Atelier Bar.

 ]]></page>
<page num="20"><![CDATA[
20

COLUMN The word mill

SWITZERLAND’S SECRET WEAPON
MILK AND NESPRESSO ARE NATIONAL TREASURES FOR THE SWISS. A DISCREET MARRIAGE OF THE TWO MAKES FOR A WINNING FORMULA.
Text Francis Dolric Illustration Mac Nooland
CAPPUCCINO, LATTE, FLAT WHITE, MACCHIATO – WITH OR WITHOUT CREAM, SPRINKLED WITH CHOCOLATE, A DASH OF VANILLA OR PINCH OF CINNAMON… BARISTAS IN EVERY CORNER OF THE WORLD, HUNCHED OVER GLEAMING MACHINES, HAVE A GIFT FOR INVENTING ORIGINAL COFFEE RECIPES. Every culture

CAFÉ RENVERSÉ

has its own speciality: from the Portuguese galão – one part espresso to three parts hot milk, served in a glass – to the Hong Kong style yuanyang – three parts Arabica, plus seven parts milky tea. Amidst all these subtly different national drinks, where does Switzerland fit in? Alongside Nespresso, milk is a national treasure. It goes without saying that these two Swiss perfections are made for one another. Even better, Switzerland has long boasted

Enduringly popular despite the onslaught of exotic innovations.

a traditional blend of coffee and hot milk – despite being less well known abroad. This drink is known as a renversé in the French-speaking parts, die Schale in German-speaking Switzerland or macchiato lungo in the Ticino area. The secret behind the recipe is, as the name suggests, a reversal of the proportions of coffee and milk – 40% coffee and 60% milk. From the pretty Genevan suburb of Carouge to the luxury hotels of Lausanne, the baristas we met assured us that the café renversé is enduringly popular despite the onslaught of exotic new innovations, and is definitely preferred at breakfast and with snacks. The success of this simple yet bold recipe is something to be proud of. ■

 ]]></page>
<page num="21"><![CDATA[
SEEONEE

 ]]></page>
<page num="22"><![CDATA[
22

 ]]></page>
<page num="23"><![CDATA[
CITY Guide

23

IN THE ETERNAL MOUNTAINS, WITH THEIR WILDFLOWERS AND NATURAL GARDENS, WHICH SEEM TO SWALLOW UP THE GRAFFITI-SCRAWLED INDUSTRIAL CATHEDRALS, LIKE A CRAVING FOR APOCALYPSE, A PATIENT ANTICIPATION OF THE END OF TIME. THE FUTURE SEEMS TO DEAL MODERNITY A BLOW, TAPPING INTO ANCIENT ENERGIES, NOT FROM THE SKY BUT FROM THE GROUND.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Text Julien Bouré Photograpy Jean-Claude Amiel

Kunsthaus Zürich has become the preferred mountain face for the ‘climbers’ of the art world, constantly in search of unconquered peaks.

CLIMBING WALL

 ]]></page>
<page num="24"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="25"><![CDATA[
H L

DESPITE ITS CULTIVATED FOLKSY CHARM AND AIRS OF AN ALPINE PARADISE, ZURICH HAS A LONG EXPERIENCE OF URBANITY.

 ]]></page>
<page num="26"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="27"><![CDATA[
ZURICH IS DOUBTLESSLY A MODERN CITY, BUT ONE LOOK AT THE TWIN SPIRES OF ITS CATHEDRAL AND YOU ARE TRANSPORTED TO THE TURQUOISE MINARETS OF SAMARKAND.

 ]]></page>
<page num="28"><![CDATA[
28

T
Wildlife nestles a few minutes from the city centre.
ZURICH ZOO SOMETIMES, IT ONLY TAKES A FEW MINUTES’ RIDE ON THE TRAMWAY TO DISENTANGLE YOURSELF FROM THE CITY WITHOUT EVEN LEAVING IT. The magniﬁcent ZURICH ZOO recreates an equatorial forest on

TANJA KOTZ
member since 2004

its hilltop location, amongst the fragrant mists and birdsong, echoing like in the nave of a cathedral. The lake exudes the serenity of a glassy sea as it laps the shores of Seefeld, the waterside neighbourhood where Tanja works. It’s in this rural neighbourhood that the MAISON LE CORBUSIER can be found. This last building designed by the Swiss architect, interior designer and urban planner was built behind the bizarre Chinese garden donated to the city by a district of Yunnan, Zurich’s twin city. Despite its impression of being an innocent little village,

Her fiery hair and soft eyes endow her with the ethereal charm of Botticelli’s Venus. Everything about this citizen of the Zurich Highlands, an Olympian back country perched on the mountain tops, seems to fit perfectly. She is an HR Manager in the hush-hush world of Swiss banking and certainly appreciates the intensity of Zurich’s cultural life, but prefers by far the purity of its lakes and forests. She loves it when the park at the Swiss National Museum is adorned with wintertime fondue tents and an ice rink straight from a Russian fairy tale, or when in summer, the chocolate-brown waters of the River Sihl cloud the waters of the Limmat. She drinks the same coffee at home and at work – her work meetings often take place at the Nespresso Boutique - enjoying it with the froth of a Latte Macchiato. But now she is pregnant, Tanja has chosen to forgo her beloved RISTRETTO in favour of the DECAFFEINATO Grand Cru.

it still offers sanctuary to intrepid designers, be they local or international. At the heart of the city’s emerging district, WALRAUD exhibits a select collection of furniture and cloth with a mischievous, youthful twist. In the midst of this organised chaos, which brings to mind a little rich girl’s bedroom, there is an extraordinary pendant whose gem, midway between opal and precious wood, turns out to be formed from multi-coloured layers of recycled magazine pages. Many Swiss fashion designers are represented at THEMA SELECTION, a former butcher’s: its ceiling decorated with scenes from folk tales, which now houses creations which are both exotic and indigenous, like Sok Hand Druck’s gorgeous prints. A stone’s throw away, the SCHWARZENBACH grocery is a national treasure, with its jumble of “colonial” goods that hasn’t aged one iota since 1864, and rows ••• and rows of dried fruits.

 ]]></page>
<page num="29"><![CDATA[
MAISON LE CORBUSIER

The renowned Swiss architect’s last work.

SCHWARZENBACH

A traditional grocery, with its exotic goods sold loose by weight.

WALDRAUD

This selection features fashion, interior design and bright ideas.

THEMA SELECTION

This former butcher’s now houses collections by Swiss designers.

 ]]></page>
<page num="30"><![CDATA[
30

H
MASCULINE CHIC REACHES FULL MATURITY HERE. THE BEST ASPECTS OF VIRILITY CAN BE FOUND IN THIS TREASURE TROVE FOR DAPPER GENTS.
JIM GERBER BAR DE L’HÔTEL HYATT

HARRY BRUPPACHER
member since 1992

This graphic designer, who has travelled the world, is proud of the cosmopolitan charms concentrated in his hometown. The cultural scene here is particularly rich, comparable to that of major cities such as London or New York. Artists and foreigners have brought an alternative universe into existence in the former “red light district” of Langstrasse, the shady areas of Zurich that no one dared acknowledge. It was as if the mountains had opened, letting the winds of change blow through from all four corners of the earth, stirring up the liquid elements deep within this ancient valley in the heart of Europe, sowing seeds of innovation. Harry has used the same machine for twenty years, and enjoys a Pure Origin ROSABAYA DE COLOMBIA at home, but prefers the more robust texture of a good RISTRETTO in the office.

The misuse of alcohol is bad for your health. Please drink responsibly.

A jeweller’s specializing in rare watches: Rolex, Daytona, Patek…

Stylish design and a relaxed atmosphere, perfect for after-work drinks.

 ]]></page>
<page num="31"><![CDATA[
31

BÄRENGASSE

This cosy restaurant boasts the hushed intimacy of a gentlemen’s club.

The modern art museum alone justifies a stay in Zurich.

KUNSTHAUS ZURICH

EDITION POPULAIRE

A selection to appeal to a masculine taste.

The flagship building with its bags made of recycled truck tarpaulin.

FREITAG

HARRY IS A CAR LOVER AND ACCESSORIES ARE NOT AN OPTIONAL EXTRA FOR HIM. HE IS CAPABLE OF BREAKING THE BANK FOR AN EXCLUSIVE WATCH, tracked down God only

knows where and how by watchmaker-jeweller
JIM GERBER. Take the Corum adorned with a

pheasant-feather dial or the priceless Bulova “Space View”, with its visible electronic mechanism, an exorbitant novelty rendered obsolete only two years after its invention by the quartz revolution. EDITION POPULAIRE’s small selection is devoted to indulging the male of the species, the uncharted region to be conquered by the lifestyle industry. The concept works so well that masculine chic reaches full maturity here. The best emblems of masculinity can be found in this treasure trove for dapper gents, with its eccentric and locally-designed products, from tank tops to kangaroo boxer-shorts, via schnapps bottles, items for polishing shoes and the barbecue-in-a-suitcase. The famous FREITAG bags cut from recycled truck tarpaulin are on sale in the brand’s biggest

boutique, a true ramshackle monument build from old containers (see ‘Citizen of Honour’ section). The KUNSTHAUS ZURICH is obviously unmissable; with its never-ending modern art collection arranged in a mix of styles, in no chronological order, serving to wrong-foot traditional academic snobbery. Haute cuisine has proved to be musician Dieter Meier’s most proﬁtable side-project (see Interview section), and one of his most successful restaurants, BÄRENGASSE, is a favourite of Harry’s when he’s not at the HYATT bar, whose back-lit onyx counter looks like it is hung with human skin. •••

 ]]></page>
<page num="32"><![CDATA[
32

L
DANIEL H

LADY MATA HARI
member since 2006

Kitsch and folklore come together in this excellent bistro.

IN THIS CITY THAT IS ALWAYS ON TIME, THERE IS A FASCINATING TIME LAG, A MISMATCH OF ERAS. FIRST, THERE’S THE FAMOUS VIADUKT, whose Dan-

She introduces herself by her stage name, as if the character and the real personality overlap instead of treading on each other’s toes. Lady Mata Hari is a professional DJ, originally from Korea and Singapore, but she has been living in Zurich from a young age. Her old cultural baggage has long lain forgotten at the back of the wardrobe – indeed her aim seems to be to fit in with the image of her adopted hometown. This big village has all the advantages of the provincial lifestyle without the drawbacks: a place which is both quiet and tolerant, a real Aladdin’s cave. It certainly is difficult to break the ice, but once you’ve found your way in, its reputation for loyalty holds true. She drinks ARPEGGIO, the violet capsule – the same colour as her hair – whose exuberant intensity mirrors that of the PIXIE which brought it into being.

tesque arches now host a picturesque farmers’ market. The nearby MARKTHALLE is the place to go and sample the legendary rack of lamb or the Croûte au fromage, after stocking up on Swiss products from the handpicked selection at the Berg und Tal delicatessen. DANIEL H evokes the close connection between kitsch and folklore, with its squinting hunting trophies and its Madonna placed in a niche lined with tawny fur. It feels like a bikers’ bar in a mountain chalet. In terms of cuisine, the organic sushi is excellent at lunchtime, and the weekly theme gives the menu its roving spirit, but

BARFUSSBAR

These public baths have a double life, metamorphosing into a nightclub after dark.

this is not as tasty as the mix of alternative creatures and predators of the ﬁnancial world that mingle here in unnatural proximity. During the day, the BARFUSSBAR is a public pool, where ladies come to paddle with the swans in the misleading tropical hues of this icy stream. However, as night falls, the wooden pool becomes tinged with more ﬁery colours, and is transformed into devilish nightclub. Another waterside establishment, the café-concert venue EL LOKAL looks like CapeHorner’s shack from the last century, crammed from ﬂoor to ceiling with souvenirs from his travels. It is impossible to resist the baroque indecency of the blood-red velvet adorning the walls of the SCHOBER confectioner’s, with its trompe-l’œil jungles, gilt coating and magniﬁcently arranged pastries. This hushed monument of Old Zurich brilliantly reveals the true nature of classicism – its constant ••• desire to shock.

 ]]></page>
<page num="33"><![CDATA[
33

MARKTHALLE

A farmers’ market and good food beneath the arches of the viaduct.

EL LOKAL

This bar is dripping with replica sailors’ trinkets.

It was probably in this kind of establishment that the macaron was born in Zurich.

SCHOBER

A SMALL PUBLIC BATH, WHERE WOMEN COME TO PADDLE WITH THE SWANS, IN THE MISLEADING TROPICAL HUES OF ITS ICY CURRENT.

 ]]></page>
<page num="34"><![CDATA[
34

G
MEDITERRANEAN CUISINE IS SERVED, PREPARED WITH VEGETABLES FROM THE KITCHEN GARDEN ALONGSIDE THE RAILWAY LINES.
WIDDER HOTEL BAR ROSSO

GIULIO PICIN
member since 2009

Giulio Picin is an atypical teacher, born in Zurich to Venetian parents, and resembling a figure from traditional African artwork, with his Mohican, his throat encircled by chains and his metal bracelets which clink like jacks. Although he is addicted to the Spanish lust for life, he always comes back to his hometown because he finds a good balance there without ever getting bored. If Venice is the fantasy of a past that is yet to come, and New York is the fiction of a future that has already had its day, then Zurich is the happy medium. People like Giulio, with Italian roots, cannot be indifferent to coffee. Giulio savours each of his fifteen daily espressos with a reverence bordering on devotion. As well as the RISTRETTO Grand Cru, served short and strong, he appreciates the guaranteed perfection of each extraction, and the freedom he has to enjoy his coffee anywhere in the world, always with the feeling of being at home.

For old-style cocktails and the customary absinthe tasting.

Sophisticated pizza in the heart of a refurbished industrial area.

 ]]></page>
<page num="35"><![CDATA[
A restaurant housed in old containers, opposite the Freitag tower.

FRAU GEROLDS GARTEN

This Italian patissier is one of the last remaining artisans in Zurich.
BOGEN 33

CAREDDA

A host of hidden treasures in this vintage furniture outlet.

THE GENIUS OF THIS “LITTLE BIG CITY” IS BETTER SEEN IN ITS KNACK FOR RECYCLING THAN IN ITS CONSTRUCTION PROJECTS: re-

claiming existing sites is a clever form of redevelopment, and it halts urban sprawl by making use of abandoned spaces. The brand new FRAU GEROLDS GARTEN has outstripped the neighbouring Freitag tower, stacking up used containers against a big fresco by the artist Sarah Parsons. Mediterranean cuisine is served, prepared with vegetables from the kitchen garden alongside the railway lines. A hundred metres away, BOGEN 33 collects vintage items just opposite the ROSSO pizzeria, whose woodburning oven nestles in premises once used by the national electricity company. While Zurich is proud of its rich cakemaking tradition, only a few ﬁrms still work like CAREDDA, a Neapolitan artisan who hand-creates each of his panettone and delicious aragoste, the puff pastry cornucopia bursting with Chantilly cream. One of the city’s most successful res-

taurants serves local, seasonal and sexy cuisine under its wine glass chandeliers. The chef at DIDI’S FRIEDEN improvises on a bold bistro cuisine, in keeping with its lava-thick stew, ﬂavoured with rich wine, blood and pure cocoa. With its moleskin wall seats, bourbon selection and absinthe fountain, the bar at the WIDDER hotel maintains a nostalgia for its golden age, between the Prohibition era and the Cuban Revolution... •••

What’s the deal with this restaurant? It’s musician Dieter Meier’s latest success.

DIDI’S FRIEDEN

 ]]></page>
<page num="36"><![CDATA[
36

M
RIO BAR

MICHAEL EURINGER & ALF HELLER
members since 2011

An American-style diner on the banks of the Sihl.

ONE OF THE BEST RESTAURANTS IN TOWN IS IN A RENOVATED HOUSE IN THE HEART OF A SOCIALLYDEPRIVED AREA. JDABURG was opened by a

group of friends, led by a capable young woman, who seems to carry this big restaurant on her small shoulders. They serve a ﬂavoursome, seasonal, inspired cuisine, including cordon-bleu with trufﬂestuffed cheese, tuna carpaccio with wasabi mousse and a delicate lemon panna cotta. “Trendy restaurants are often a let-down,” says Alf. “Either the waiters drift around in their dinner jackets, or the prices are astronomical, or the quality of the food is debatable. Here, a minor miracle is performed every day. And no one is ever out of place, whether they come in slippers or stilettos.” The

One is a shaven-headed accountant for a bank. The other is a hairdresser. Needless to say that the pair were not naturally cut out to meet. But as is so often in this city, a deeper reality lies beneath the surface. To a certain extent, Zurich is to Switzerland what Milan is to Italy: while neither of them is the most beautiful location in their respective countries, they are both the most exciting place to be, a bit like an oyster whose uninviting shell opens to reveal the delicious flesh within, and occasionally conceals a beautiful pearl. Despite the metallic purity of their Aluminium PIXIE, Alf and Michael appreciate the smoothness of the VOLLUTO and the VIVALTO LUNGO, which they take long, with no sugar but with a drop of milk and some little chocolates. They also enjoy discovering the new blends of aromas.

KAFI SCHNAPS

For its excellent breakfast on the hills above Zurich.

Inspired cuisine on the outskirts of the city.

JDABURG

excellent TIMES restaurant shares its walls with a paraphernalia of precious objects, such as balsamic fragrances from the Farmacia Ss Annunziata in Florence, scented candles from Secrets d’Apothicaires in Grasse and art deco snuffers with motherof-pearl handles. Diners enjoy a wonderful meal beneath the enormous seventies-style chandeliers, whilst admiring their reﬂections in the lacquered tables, glazed with hull varnish. On the sleepy hills above the city, KAFI SCHNAPS boasts ﬁve cosy little ﬁrst-ﬂoor bedrooms above a black-and-white tiled café, like a 1950s New York diner. The little RIO BAR snack bar is as clear as a glass bubble, like an aquarium lit up from the inside. The romantic FISCHER’S FRITZ bistro is lapped by the waters of the lake. Finally, in the heart of the LÖWENBRÄU AREAL COMPLEX, one of the largest modern art institutions in Europe is hosted by the retailing group Migros, a pillar of the Swiss middle classes. ■

 ]]></page>
<page num="37"><![CDATA[
37

DINERS ENJOY A WONDERFUL MEAL BENEATH THE ENORMOUS SEVENTIES-STYLE CHANDELIERS, WHILST ADMIRING THEIR REFLECTIONS IN THE LACQUERED TABLES, GLAZED WITH HULL VARNISH.

FISCHER’S FRITZ

The tables of this waterside restaurant are lapped by the lake.

LÖWENBRÄU AREAL COMPLEX

One of the most fascinating modern Art museums in Europe.

This restaurant is tucked inside a cabinet of curiosities.

TIMES

 ]]></page>
<page num="38"><![CDATA[
I N T E R V I E W AT T H E N E S P R E S S O B O U T I Q U E I N

ZURICH
René Palli, Head Barista at the Boutique situated in Z u r i c h ’s b u s i n e s s d i s t r i c t , w o r k s s o m e b e a u t i f u l patterns into the foam of his cappuccinos. H e t e l l s u s a b o u t S w i t z e r l a n d ’s f i r s t N e s p r e s s o b a r.
RENÉ PALLI, WHY NESPRESSO?

RENÉ PALLI: The story begins in 2007, with the opening of Switzerland’s first Nespresso bar. I had already acquired a variety of experience in the catering sector. I had been trained as part of a kitchen team, and completed a course of study at a hotel school. That’s where I discovered my real vocation in the service sector. I had worked as a Head Waiter in several establishments before reading a Nespresso advertisement looking for staff who were equally well-qualified in both hospitality and catering. And that’s how I became a barista.
WHERE IS THE BOUTIQUE?

WHERE CAN I ENJOY A NESPRESSO COFFEE IN ZURICH?
THE RESTAURANT AT THE DOLDER GRAND

R. P.: We’re in Zurich’s financial district, less than a minute’s walk from the Paradeplatz. It’s the heart of the city, and maybe even of the world!
WHAT KIND OF PEOPLE NORMALLY CALL IN?

The young prodigy Heiko Nieder (see our Chef section) leads the team at this prestigious establishment located near Zurich Zoo. Here he prepares a unique cuisine which has earned him two Michelin stars.
MESA

R. P.: At opening time, our clientele is largely made up of businessmen who come to meet up over an Espresso and some croissants. Later on come our regulars, ladies, friends and tourists, who tend to order cappuccinos and latte macchiatos when it’s cold, and cappuccino frappés and ice vanillas when the first rays of sunlight start to break through. Not to mention our many seasonal inhouse creations. The room is often buzzing with the sound of several languages, like a Tower of Babel, and I regularly have to put aside my native German in order to answer questions in English, French or Italian...
WHAT ARE THE MOST POPULAR ITEMS ON YOUR MENU?

Marcus Lindner’s flagship restaurant brings a delightfully fresh, contemporary Mediterranean twist to a classic gastronomic repertoire.
WIRTSCHAFT ZUM WIESENGRUND

Just outside the city near Lake Zurich, this traditional flagstone house conceals an unexpected culinary experience with Chef Peter Hussong’s menu and a dazzling wine cellar.
BAUR AU LAC

R. P.: In the morning, the financial early-risers tend to go for a strong Indriya from India, Ristretto or Arpeggio. Then in the afternoon, the trend shifts towards the sweeter Pure Origin Espressos, such as the Rosabaya de Colombia and the Dulsão do Brasil…

Linger over a coffee in Zurich’s legendary luxury hotel, which has hosted the upper crust of the past two centuries beneath its old gilding.

Find all the addresses referred to above on our map at the back of the magazine.

 ]]></page>
<page num="39"><![CDATA[
39

 ]]></page>
<page num="40"><![CDATA[
40

CITIZENS of Honour
DANIEL & MARKUS FREITAG IN 7 DATES
Top Cat’, their first messenger bag, from recycled truck tarpaulin; it remains their best-selling item. 2003 Their original model becomes part of the permanent collection at New York’s Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) 2006 The Freitag tower is built: a stack of shipping containers which houses their flagship store. 2010 Their seasonal collection, ‘Freitag Reference’, is launched. 2011 Due to lack of space they relocate to bigger factory premises of 7500 m².
1971 Markus is born. 1972 Daniel is born. 1993 They create ‘F13

 ]]></page>
<page num="41"><![CDATA[
Designers and brothers Daniel and Markus Freitag make high quality accessories using recycled truck tarpaulin. After making their debut at the Museum of Modern Art in New York and building a reputation the world over, these two Swiss pioneers are on the trail of Europe’s heavy goods vehicles.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Text Julien Bouré Photography Jean-Claude Amiel
SOME CITIES ARE VAIN BEYOND BELIEF. THE SPLENDOURS OF PARIS, NEW YORK, LONDON OR ROME CAN SOMETIMES COME ACROSS MORE AS DISPLAYS OF STRENGTH, ALMOST REDUCING THEIR BEAUTY TO A CRUEL, POWERFUL SEDUCTION. Other

cities, such as Zurich, greet visitors with a vulnerable innocence: any pretensions are as fragile and translucent as tracing paper. Such cities can be caught by surprise, with disarming naivety. Progress is made without posturing, unaffected by onlookers. Zurich has never tried to follow trends. Rather than seeking to move with the ﬁckle humours of ever-marching time, the city has wisely waited its turn, its

cityscape rarely contributing to the experiments of modernity. There have admittedly been several beautiful architectural imports – the French Belle Époque, Italian neo-baroque and German Bauhaus – but their austere appearance brings to mind an exotic plant struggling to acclimatise to the rareﬁed atmosphere of the high mountains. Yet today’s world ﬁts Zurich like a glove: in this post-industrial, ecological, conservative era, the lack of affectation and the frugality of the city can be perceived as a welcome soberness. Amidst the uncertainty of the economic crisis, proﬂigate humanity will need to rediscover this purifying simplicity. •••

 ]]></page>
<page num="42"><![CDATA[
42

Daniel

Markus

 ]]></page>
<page num="43"><![CDATA[
POST POSTINDU INDUSTRITR AL
ELEGANT RECYCLING

Daniel and Markus Freitag are old hands at making a virtue of necessity, and in their way, they embody the Swiss mindset whose genius lies in its incredible economy of means. These masters of design have built a career on a variation of the messenger bag, the ubiquitous satchel slung over every postman’s shoulder the world over. But the reinvention of this cult item lies less in the success of design than in the Freitag brothers’ choice of material. Their design was to go down in the history of luxury accessories, as did the saddlery of Hermès, Louis Vuitton’s luggage or Gucci’s leather goods, in days gone by. The concept,

The Freitag brothers had just invented elegant recycling.

which the two brothers came up with nearly twenty years ago while still graphic arts students, is truly visionary: looking for a case to protect their designs, they created a bag made from the tarpaulin of a curtain-sided truck lined with bicycle inner tube, using a seatbelt for the strap. Not only were these materials readily available for very small sums, the main ingredient also combined the hard-wearing, waterproof qualities of rubber, the resilient colours of plastic and the texture of quality leather. It came with a lifetime guarantee and any tears were easily sealed using a touch of coloured resin... The Freitag brothers had just invented elegant recycling, bringing new life to the residue of the road – as a useful and decorative, practical and desirable cult object.
GETTING THEIR HANDS DIRTY

New York’s Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) recognised this masterpiece by including the brothers’ ﬁrst creation (which has since been named the “F13 Top Cat”) in their permanent collection. The Museum of Design Zurich also recently ran an exhibition on the two young heroes of Swiss visual identity. After all, the bags breathe life into recycled materials, stitched together with white thread with a care which prevents them from looking like a patchwork of cold meat or Frankenstein’s monster. Each year, around 400 tonnes of tarpaulin are painstakingly cut by hand, with the skill of a butcher carving his prime cuts. It takes a real understanding of graphics to know when to cut through the middle of an emblem or how to choose the most signiﬁcant letters or twist the meaning of a fragment of a logo... and these are the elements which make each bag a unique work of art. The tarpaulin itself is not chosen at random. Truck tarpaulin is considered the most durable and exhibits the most interesting wear and tear after it has been exposed to the elements for ﬁve to seven years. This ﬁnish lends the material a more natural •••

 ]]></page>
<page num="44"><![CDATA[
44

ECOECOFRIEND IEND LY
appearance than the faux-worn look of stone-washed jeans and proves that it truly is used canvas, without which the bags would just be yet another greenwashed product. The production line operates a just-in-time system, keeping pace with the arrival of materials. The biggest problem with these spontaneous deliveries lies in their excessive uniformity (lots of blue, red and offwhite); to ﬂesh out the palette a little, teams are sent out to motorway toll stations around Europe in search of rare colours (like black, which hauliers avoid because of its heat-absorbing tendencies). The style ofﬁces of the factory are a sight to behold, strewn with periodicals specialising in heavy goods vehicles and young designers returning from some arty café ready to get their hands dirty working with the latest highway trends.
ODDS AND ENDS

The Freitag brothers have already developed around ﬁfty prototypes which are split into two categories: a masculine range which makes use of the prints on the tarpaulin, and a more classic range with block colours that allow the quality of the exotic material to shine through. The former line conveys the rugged charm of rust and deindustrialisation, the latter a purity somewhere between leather and mineral. Offcuts are used to make wallets or mobile phone cases, and any leftovers can be recycled once the PVC and polyester have been separated. The whole enterprise works as a large-scale salvage operation. Behind the raw concrete walls and shining metal doors of the factory, 4 million litres of rainwater are harvested and ﬁltered every year. Even before moving to this site - which would not look out of place in Silicon Valley - the factory was housed in a pyramid of seventeen containers stacked up alongside train tracks. This skyscraper of odds and ends is now the brand’s ﬂagship store (it has eight other outlet stores under the same name in Zurich, Davos, Berlin, Hamburg, Cologne, New York and Tokyo). It is also Zurich’s most interesting building, and was probably its highest tower before the nearby construction of a mirrored glass monolith suddenly dwarfed it by comparison. Most importantly, the Freitag tower managed to single-handedly transform the drab appearance of this neglected part of town, which has now become one of the most sophisticated areas of the city. All it took was juxtaposing one colour against another for a new perspective. Successful recycling is all about transforming appearances, just as the same landscape looks different when accompanied by electronic music rather than an aria... The brothers are today’s great transformers. n

 ]]></page>
<page num="45"><![CDATA[
D D-

Every year, around 400 tonnes of tarpaulin are painstakingly cut by hand.

 ]]></page>
<page num="46"><![CDATA[
46

SWISS ARMY KNIFE

In a neutral country, the army has to rely on its own strength and every soldier must be independent. The history of this knife goes back to the end of the 19th century when Switzerland’s military placed an order for a universal tool that its troops could use for a range of purposes - from cutting their steak to dismantling their rifle. The solution was soon provided by a small manufacturer in the Canton of Schwyz, from which Switzerland got its name. Victorinox’s original model included a knife, a can opener, a flat-head screwdriver and a punch... but believe it or not, no bottle opener! Nowadays there are dozens of versions, some much more “urban” which come with accessories such as a watch, a pen or a USB flash drive…

Priceless jewel or unnecessary extravagance? In any case, Swiss Made original creations have always been created with expert precision, ensuring that their bright ideas are always valued.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Text Julien Bouré Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

NATIONAL

 ]]></page>
<page num="47"><![CDATA[
STYLE Swiss Made

47

CARAN D’ACHE PENCILS
The legendary manufacturer Caran d’Ache, from Thônex, has been the near-exclusive purveyor of coloured pencils and quality ball-point pens to artists, school pupils and stationers for almost a century. They were the ones who sold the first mechanical pencil in 1930, a year after it had been invented in Geneva. Graphic design was taking off and its artists were soon drawn to this invention, turning this modern-day quill into their symbol. Even the Swiss postal service recently paid tribute to this original expression of national genius by creating a special stamp. Although the mechanical lead-propelling system has never changed, a prestigious metal plating has long since replaced its early Bakelite body.

 ]]></page>
<page num="48"><![CDATA[
48

SWATCH WATCH
The Swiss watch-making industry is concentrated in French-speaking regions and its traditions can be traced to the Theocratic Republic of Geneva. Under Calvin’s reforms, residents were forbidden to show the slightest sign of vanity and city goldsmiths were forced to turn their hand to the precision craft of watchmaking which was better suited to the strict morals of the time. Nowadays, Switzerland is home to the largest watch-making company on the planet. The Swatch Group sell items that range in price from “28 euros to the sky” and have helped revitalise the national watch-making industry after a century wrought with difficulty. The desire for independence, a sentiment so dear to their home country, has even led the company to create its own bank.

Switzerland is home to the largest watchmaking company on the planet.

 ]]></page>
<page num="49"><![CDATA[
49

NESPRESSO CAPSULE
Nespresso’s aluminium capsules are yet more evidence of Alpine genius, giving our coffee that freshly-ground taste for months. Its design incorporates both straight lines and curves, and illustrates the perfect simplicity of this hugely successful product. Since hitting the market at the end of the 1980s, the capsules have won over several million coffee connoisseurs worldwide. The capsules are designed to protect and recreate the aromatic richness of each Grand Cru, with Nespresso’s latest treasure encased in plain aluminium with a simple transparent coating. Because its most precious riches can be found inside: Hawaii Kona Special Reserve.

 ]]></page>
<page num="50"><![CDATA[
50

SWISS KIRSCH

This cherry brandy is produced in most German-speaking parts of the world, but hits the heights of excellence in Switzerland. Maybe this is because it is a vital ingredient in another national treasure: cheese fondue.

PRALINE STICKS

Praline is a national delicacy. Every Swiss confectioner produces their own praline-filled, hazelnut-sprinkled chocolate bar, creating a foil-wrapped national treasure.

BAISER DE MOUSSE

This dessert is known around the world as “Parisian Macaroons” and was invented in 1957 by the Luxembourg confectioner, Camille Studer. The recipe was then improved in Sprüngli’s kitchens in Zurich.

SKIN CAVIAR

La Prairie laboratory created this skincare line with active ingredients from beluga caviar, after noticing that women working packing sturgeon eggs had especially beautiful hands.

 ]]></page>
<page num="51"><![CDATA[
51

THRIFTY PEELER

This handy item has all the characteristics of a successful design - it is useful, effective and simple. The design of the Rex peeler was registered in 1947 by a little-known citizen of Davos by the name of Alfred Neweczerzal. It deserves a place in the pantheon of eternal inventions, somewhere between the wheel and aspirin, for its service to humanity. The peeler alone can be credited with saving millions of hours of “potato duty”, but its best quality is its thriftiness. Just think how many thousands of tonnes of edible matter have already been saved from the inexpert fumbling of a clumsy knife. This instrument can peel fruit and vegetables as easily as a hand-held razor can freshen up a bearded chin. It has become a classic kitchen utensil and is celebrated throughout the world. This golden version can be found in the Zurich Museum of Design.

 ]]></page>
<page num="52"><![CDATA[
CHEF TO THE GREAT AND THE GOOD
Heiko Nieder took charge of The Restaurant kitchens in 2008. This ambitious restaurant is part of Dolder Grand, the enormous palace overlooking Zurich. Take a look at how the other half eat.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Text Julien Bouré Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

 ]]></page>
<page num="53"><![CDATA[
CHEF Heiko Nieder

53

HEIKO NIEDER IN 7 DATES
1972 Born in Reinbek in the 1990 Trains at the Vier Jahreszeiten

outskirts of Hamburg.

hotel in Hamburg, then in several Michelin-starred establishments: Le Canard (Hamburg), Zur Traube (Grevenbroich), and Vau (Berlin). 2002 Head chef at L’Orquivit (Bonn). 2003 Named “Discovery of the Year” by Gault&Millau. 2005 Awarded his first Michelin star. 2008 Head of The Restaurant, the fine dining location at the Dolder Grand (Zurich). 2011 Awarded a second star by the Michelin Guide.

 ]]></page>
<page num="54"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="55"><![CDATA[
55

TO FIND THE REAL ENGINE ROOM OF THIS HUGE S PA C E S H I P, Y O U H A V E T O TA K E A P E E K T H R O U G H BASEMENT WINDOWS, PEER THROUGH PORTHOLES AND CLIMB EACH OF THE FIRE ESCAPES.

ACROSS THE HORIZON, THE ETERNAL SNOWS LOOK LIKE THE SEAMS OF SOME CELESTIAL MINERAL DEPOSIT. LAKE ZURICH STANDS OUT AGAINST THE MOUNTAINS LIKE A FRAGMENT OF FALLEN SKY, REFLECTING THE UPWARD-SWEEPING HILLS, GREEN AS THE ELYSIAN FIELDS. This heavenly scenery

A

can be best appreciated from a vast balcony, accessed via a futuristic walkway which calls to mind the Batmobile’s launch pad. You have now reached the threshold of a fantastic castle to rival Bruce Wayne’s manor: the Dolder Grand, Switzerland’s largest hotel, whose legendary panorama is the envy of the world. The Empress Sissi, Richard Wagner, Franz Liszt, Alfred Hitchcock, Persian shahs and Abyssinian emperors have gazed over this masterpiece. It is a hard act to follow for the 40,000 m² of the palace, which is filled with priceless works of art. From the luminous landscapes of Camille Pissarro to the dreamlike precision of Salvador Dalí, the studious hallucinations of Jean Dubuffet and the infantile kitsch of Takashi Murakami, the Dolder Grand denies itself no luxury. But to find the real engine room of this huge spaceship, modernised by Norman Foster’s architects, you have to take a peek through basement windows, peer through portholes and climb each of the fire escapes.
A MUSCULAR CULINARY MACHINE

their breath in the presence of his ample yet precise movements, as sharp as the blow of a sword... Heiko Nieder is not burdened by the vanities of regional fare: his cuisine is conceived in keeping with his wayfaring nature (after training in Hamburg and Berlin, he was chef at L’Orquivit, a highly-regarded restaurant in Bonn). The menu blends rigorously selected local ingredients with a multitude of exotic marvels, such as pearly line-caught turbot served with miniature garnishes prepared with a diamond-dealer’s pliers; or Breton lobster with strawberries, probably a homage to one of the glories of French Nouvelle Cuisine, the famous vanilla lobster cooked by chef Alain Senderens. It is essentially a true hotel menu, fitting perfectly with the international and eclectic inclination of this city of refuge: Zurich, where twenty minutes’ walk takes you out of the city – a summary of the world, the gathering place of high society.
CARDINAL VIRTUE

Even when the kitchen is a hive of activity, chef Heiko Nieder’s stoves glisten like a hall of mirrors. The palace has placed quite some kitchen at the disposal of this young, thoughtful German chef, who has only just turned forty and came to the hotel in 2008. Other kitchens relieve him of the daily trials of breakfast and room service, leaving him free to dedicate all his time to his “cuisine”. The prestigious establishment, soberly named “The Restaurant”, discreetly embodies this extravagant hotel in its every detail. That idea more than anything else is what motivates this muscular culinary machine. The team are a sight to behold, as they strut about in full uniform, not a hair out of place, then suddenly spring into action with the discipline of a film crew, where each person in his or her mysterious role contributes to the success of the final performance. Every so often, the director takes the camera, and everyone holds

In order to gain a better understanding of Switzerland’s biggest city, one might compare it to another protestant metropolis. Amsterdam is its polar opposite, a city where you can see right into the houses, and the walls between each window are almost like frames. In days gone by, this strange architecture meant that occupants’ integrity was subject to the prying gaze of passers-by. Nothing could have been stranger to the former inhabitants of Zurich than to parade their virtues in the public arena. After all, whereas the middle classes of Amsterdam made a living from trade, their Swiss counterparts were expert bankers. The cardinal virtue of the former was reputation; the latter, discretion. It is something of a paradox that such a reserved culture was so successful in attracting fortunes from around the world. Zurich is hardly fond of excess, as its grand yet unadorned houses attest. The city has created its own form of luxury which is modest yet efficient: the approval of its citizens, the only people on earth bored by wealth. It almost brings to mind the court at Versailles, where the Sun King won the unstinting loyalty of the most feared lords by handing out courtly privileges, such as the right to sit down in his presence. •••

 ]]></page>
<page num="56"><![CDATA[
56

EVEN WHEN THE KITCHEN IS A H I V E O F A C T I V I T Y, C H E F HEIKO NIEDER’S STOVES GLISTEN LIKE A HALL OF MIRRORS.

 ]]></page>
<page num="57"><![CDATA[
P
PILGRIMAGE

The problem of copious wealth is reaching the limits of what it can buy. What could be more frustrating than not being able to enjoy one’s money? In days gone by, the protestant city amassed wealth only to resist it. Its piety invented the inﬁnite accumulation of capital, replacing spending with investment to escape from the former’s promises, as insubstantial as evening drizzle on the lake. Millionaires searching for meaning come from around the world hoping to ﬁnd the miracle of normality: King Midas would have loved to feel something other than gold beneath his ﬁngers. Heiko Nieder is thus charged with satisfying a difficult clientele seeking simplicity. Diners must be served without uncalled-for familiarity, and their whims flattered without any guilt-tripping. They do not want to feel trapped by flagrant indulgence, and sincerity is all they appreciate. Perhaps by dint of feeding the fascination of the masses, and thus encouraging cheap imitations, they fear they too will end up trapped in kitsch. They dread discovering they have signed up to a soap opera instead of a blockbuster. The Dolder Grand does not compromise on any element which might set their minds at rest: a simple yet luxurious menu, cautiously ambitious and carefully generous, yet leaving room for spontaneity, right down to the balanced selection of coffees, which are extracted at a specific temperature and prepared by the Nespresso Aguila machine which can whip up any number of recipes with mathematical precision. And from time to time, this harnessed desire for power steps on the accelerator: the race car revs at the red light, reaches top speed in half a second and only levels out at the very limit of what is possible, restricted only by the cramped alleys and watchful eye of radars. n

 ]]></page>
<page num="58"><![CDATA[
58

CHEESE AND JUNIPER BERRY TART
SERVES 4-6 – PREPARATION TIME: 30 min COOLING TIME: 1 hr COOKING TIME: 55 min + 1 hr 30 min

For the tart: pre-heat the oven to 175 °C (gas mark 4-5). n Mix together 500 g (1 lb 1 ½ oz) cream cheese, 70 g (2 ½ oz) sugar, 50 g (1 ¾ oz) cornflour, 100 g (3 ½ oz) single cream, 50 g (1 ¾ oz) cream, 1 yoghurt and 3 egg yolks. n Beat 4 egg whites with 90 g (3 ¼ oz) of sugar until stiff then add to the mixture. Add the juice and zest of one lemon, mix and pour into a greased tin. Cook for 40 minutes until golden. Leave to cool. For the crumble: mix 50 g (1 ¾ oz) cane sugar with 50 g (1 ¾ oz) soft butter, 50 g (1 ¾ oz) flour, 50 g (1 ¾ oz) ground almonds, 2 g salt and 5 g crushed juniper berries. Roll into a ball and refrigerate for 1 hour. Break the dough into crumbs and cook for 15 minutes at 180 °C (gas mark 6). For the cream: mix 275 g (10 oz) cream cheese with 80 g (3 oz) sugar and one teaspoon of flour. Beat one egg with one yolk and stir into the mixture. Add 20 g (¾ oz) cream, ½ teaspoon candied lemons and the ground seeds of half a vanilla pod. Mix and pour into a greased tin. Heat in a bain-marie for 1 ½ hours in an oven heated to 90 °C (gas mark 3). Leave to cool and top the tart with this creamy mixture, sprinkled with the crumble. This dessert is served with marinated loquats, a compote of wild herbs and sorrel sorbet.

TURBOT A LA GRENOBLOISE
SERVES 4 – PREPARATION TIME: 20 min COOKING TIME: 45 min

Peel the zest from four lemons, keeping the pith and the pulp for the juice. n Place the zest and the pith in separate pots of cold water, quickly bring to the boil then drain. Repeat four times. The fifth time, cook both together over a low heat with 50 g (1 ¾ oz) sugar for around 45 minutes. Drain. n Mix to a fine purée with the lemon juice and a pinch of salt. n Beat 5 egg yolks in a dish in a bain-marie, along with 1 tablespoon of white wine and 2 tablespoons of caper juice. Gradually add 80 g (3 oz) butter and 20 g (¾ oz) lemon olive oil; the sauce should thicken like a hollandaise sauce. Season. Keep on the heat. n Salt 4 x 80 g (3 oz) turbot filets and pan-fry on each side in 50 g (1 ¾ oz) butter over a medium heat. Take off the heat and sprinkle with lemon zest. n Serve with the lemon purée, the sauce, chopped parsley and fried croutons. This fish is served with a brown butter emulsion and the foamed caper sauce. THESE HEIKO NIEDER RECIPES HAVE BEEN ADAPTED.

LOBSTER, STRAWBERRIES & TARRAGON

SERVES 4 – PREPARATION TIME: 30 min COOKING TIME: 2 hr COOLING TIME: 1hr + 1hr

Wash 2 beetroot, wrap in tin foil and bake in the oven for 2 hours at 180 °C. Peel and dice. n Marinate 100 g (3 ½ oz) finely chopped strawberries in 1 tablespoon of raspberry vinegar, 100 ml (3 ½ fl oz) olive oil and 5 drops of lime juice. n Place 2.6 kg (1 lb 5 oz) lobsters in salted boiling water. Boil for 4-5 minutes. n Plunge the lobsters in salted icy water. Remove the shell and cut into medallions. n Mix 600 ml (21 fl oz) lemon olive oil with 100 ml (3 ½ fl oz) stock. Add the juice of one lime and marinate the medallions in this mixture for one hour. n Blend 2 stalks of tarragon with 250 ml (8 ¾ fl oz) water and 3 g sea salt. Soften 3 gelatine leaves in cold water then dissolve in hot water, and add to the tarragon sauce. n Pour this mixture into a siphon, refrigerate for 30 minutes then shake the siphon and pour the contents onto a plate. Refrigerate for one hour to allow the mousse to set. Chop the mousse. n Serve with the marinated medallions, the beetroot and the strawberries. This starter is served with beetroot chips, nasturtium flowers and mustard.

 ]]></page>
<page num="59"><![CDATA[
H E I K O N I E D E R I S N O T B U R D E N E D B Y T H E VA N I T I E S O F R E G I O N A L FA R E : H I S C U I S I N E I S C O N C E I V E D I N K E E P I N G W I T H H I S N AT U R E .

The misuse of alcohol is dangerous for your health. Please drink responsibly.

A FREE REIN

Giving this young chef freedom to be creative has paid off. He has just been awarded two stars by the Michelin Guide.

 ]]></page>
<page num="60"><![CDATA[
In Zurich, careful attention is paid to the aesthetic side of working life. It’s not just the ﬁne arts and haute couture that seduce the eye here: there is a real sense of style in the hotel sector, press outlets, catering venues and even business centres.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Text Julien Bouré Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

STYLE ICONS
MORITZ SCHMID: INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER

As he sees it, designers are not supposed to develop a certain style. Their job is to create a concept and then make it a reality as simply as possible using the right material. The ﬁne arts are a kind of relentless daydream, a poetic dialogue between the imagination and the material. Design is the act of making the latter submit to good sense. “Instead of starting off with a technique or a material, I imagine the object-to-be in as complete a situation as possible.” That is how he came up with the ingenious piece of furniture that is his solid ash wood chair, which you can sit on sideways and slide around freely. Rather than immobilising you in a speciﬁc posture, the round seat invites you to relax, guiding you like a handrail as you turn around without forcing you into any particular direction. The back of the chair sits quite low at rib-level, so that you can rest your arm or elbows on it. But design can also have a purely aesthetic function. To this end, Moritz replaced the hooks on his coat stand with something like metal ears: rather than just hanging there, the clothes look as if they are being worn.

 ]]></page>
<page num="61"><![CDATA[
DESIGN The new scene in Zurich

61

KASPAR MULLER: ARTIST

For this artist from Schaffhausen, a quiet, pretty market town known largely for being close to the Rhine Falls, Zurich is a surreal city. But the fascination it arouses can either stimulate or block an artist’s imagination. It’s essentially all about money. There’s too much of it, and yet never enough to stamp out greed, which crawls around beneath the façade of outward appearances: the closelyguarded secrets, punctuality, rolling gaits and the pure water of the lake. “There is more than enough kitsch in Zurich to feed a soap opera script, thanks to the have-nots, whose one dream is to join the world of the rich.” One of his main artistic projects is the ﬁlm “Colmar & Strasbourg”, which juxtaposes visits to two beautiful French cities. The uncanny similarity of their canals, gabled façades and corbelled balconies ﬁ nally merges these two tourist sites together, which ultimately come to resemble the same soulless theme park.

 ]]></page>
<page num="62"><![CDATA[
A FOREIGNER’S PERSPECTIVE

ALFREDO HÄBERLI: DESIGNER – INTERIOR DECORATOR

This Argentinian from Córdoba, where the pampas meet the foothills of the Andes, explains with aristocratic composure (a far cry from the stunning and ﬁerce delivery of the natives of Buenos Aires) that his simple craftsman’s studio in Zurich is currently working on orders from around ﬁfteen countries. These projects range from creating jewellery collections to decorating a 126-room hotel. The 25hours hotel chain has given him carte blanche to breathe life into the soulless building it has just acquired in the new district of Zurich. He has therefore designed the entire interior himself, from the most important features right down to the tiniest detail: curtain prints, signage, paintings, lights, bedding, ﬁttings... a complete experience involving more than 70 custom-built creations, a feat not seen since Arne Jacobsen and de Gioponti’s exploits last century. “I think that the project is in keeping with the way I see the city – from the perspective of a resident foreigner rather than a seasoned local. It’s a perspective that is still inspired by Zurich’s minimalism, uniformity and cautious exoticism, and not immune to its charms.”

 ]]></page>
<page num="63"><![CDATA[
63

 ]]></page>
<page num="64"><![CDATA[
64

MARK: LUXURY CATERER

ANA ROLDAN: POLITICALLY-ENGAGED MULTIMEDIA ARTIST

This enigmatic character reveals only his ﬁrst name and a short description of his strange profession: hospitality expert. As he would have it, a successful catering service can be summed up in three points: the quality of the food, service, and the satisfaction of the guests. “We provide an aesthetic concept to those who have the means to pay for it, but who don’t necessarily have a clear idea of what they want. I go beyond supplying them with food and a team of waiters – I help them make their dream a reality.” From a long, relaxed cocktail party to the careful etiquette of French service, Mark says that he draws inspiration from the ‘kuroko’, the discreet servant who appears on stage in Japanese theatre, wrapped entirely in black. The audience understands his purely logistical role and ends up no longer seeing him, in the same way that the retina learns to ignore its blind spot. For Mark, the waiting staff need to know how to disappear without ceasing to exist. They have succeeded when it seems like everything has happened automatically.

This conceptual artist from Mexico specialises in dealing with social themes through installations and posters, and regularly returns to explore her native continent. Living in Zurich, a city which is both international and slightly insular, allows her to gather herself without being totally cut off from the rest of the world. One of the main aspects of her varied lines of work is studying the spontaneous birth of the Modernist movements in Latin America before they were besieged by nationalist ideologies, or patriotically cross-bred with local folklore. “I was interested in the student revolts of 1968, which affected different countries in different ways. In the USA, the movement was paciﬁst and anti-racist, while its French equivalent was more political, and the Eastern Bloc had its ﬂeeting Prague Spring... it was with the Mexican equivalent, which ended in a terrible loss of human life, that I ﬁrst explored the way a worldwide phenomenon touched my native country.”

CARMEN AND URS GREUTMANN: OFFICE SPACE DESIGNERS

KAZU HUGGLER: FASHION DESIGNER

This couple, who split their time between their Zurich studio and their teaching duties at the Academy of Fine Arts in Munich, specialise in the design of work spaces. They appreciate the city’s capacity to integrate new forms of creativity, by virtue of a mindset which is more rational than emotional. The two designers create furniture and arrange their disposition at the request of businesses. A motivating environment must be inspired by the pattern of a working day, which is more likely to resemble a meandering path than a boulevard: there are periods of intense thought, breaks, informal conversations, formal meetings, and much more besides. The cocoon in which the Greutmanns are posing is a good illustration of this. It’s a swing seat made from security seals (the kind of cheap, hard-wearing fastenings used by airport boutiques). Far from being counterproductive, it’s a reminder that no one can stay glued to their laptop screen for hours at a time.

This raven-haired, milk-skinned dress designer grew up in both Tokyo and Zurich. Kazu now weaves these two rich cultures together to obtain a truly composite fabric. For her, European tailors are the best in the world. It is they that created the made-to-measure technique, which is an anatomical art, a search for a body’s identity. In the Japanese tradition, good taste resides in concealment. Fitted tailoring is unheard of amongst those who make kimonos, an elegant yet shapeless outﬁt, which enwraps rather than clothes the wearer. “My approach is anchored in the past, but that doesn’t prevent me from bringing it up to date. For example, I use inkjet technology, which allows me to create prints with photographic precision.” She also allows herself a few artistic indulgences, such as this silk teddy jacket embroidered with catﬁsh and chrysanthemum motifs, a fashion homage to the brutally dandy gangs of rockabilly thugs who square up to each other in Yoyogi Park.

 ]]></page>
<page num="65"><![CDATA[
BALANCING ‘FULL’ AND ‘EMPTY’
MARCUS KRAFT: GRAPHIC DESIGNER

This young artistic director works for magazines and develops editorial concepts for various companies. He compares his work in publishing to that of a theatre director. He coordinates a team of editors, photographers and illustrators, monitors the graphic balance between image, blank space and “grey” text, and gives the general layout a spirited, intelligent touch. One of his more unusual recent projects, although still within his line of work, was reorganizing the layout of a toy shop. The challenge of balancing full and empty space is at the heart of every instance of graphic design: every logo and symbol starts off life as a careful mix of black and white. It is the same with developing typefaces – an unremitting task involving meticulous examination of an angle or a curve, ﬁne or thickset feet, and the space between two letters, where the slightest change can render the font classic or dated, contemporary or experimental. It makes sense that this should become a speciality of Switzerland, a country where everything is so well organised. Marcus’ passion for calligraphy has inspired him to write a book, which has just been published. “Don’t Eat the Yellow Snow” is a collection of adages taken from pop songs, such as the title of the book, a quotation from Frank Zappa that is often heard in Swiss ski schools.

 ]]></page>
<page num="66"><![CDATA[
THIS GLACIAL COUNTRY DOES NOT ENJOY ITS EVERLASTING SNOW. IT HAS ALWAYS PREFERRED THE BUTTERY SMOOTHNESS OF “BAISERS DE MOUSSE” ZURICH-STYLE MACARONS - AND THEIR WARMER COUNTERPARTS, SUCH AS AARGAU CARROT CAKE, GINGERBREAD OR CHESTNUT VERMICELLI, WHICH MELT IN THE MOUTH LIKE A SPONGE FINGER.
Production Marie Leteuré Stylist Élodie Rambaud Photography Jérôme Bilic
CARAC CHOCOLATE TARTLETS & ARPEGGIO

recipe page 70

Ritual Ristretto cup (Nespresso - design by Andrée Putman). Bowl (Mud Australia). The misuse of alcohol is dangerous for your health. Please drink responsibly.

 ]]></page>
<page num="67"><![CDATA[
GOURMET Coffee
MILANESE CHRISTMAS BISCUITS & FORTISSIO LUNGO CAFE RENVERSE
MAKES AROUND 40 BISCUITS PREPARATION TIME: 20 min - COOLING TIME: 30 min COOKING TIME: 10 min INGREDIENTS: 1 Fortissio Lungo capsule per person (1 x 110 ml) -

67

160 ml of hot milk For the biscuits: 125 g (4 ½ oz) soft butter - 1 egg - 120 g (4 oz) sugar a pinch of salt - the zest of one small lemon - 250 g (9 oz) ﬂour 50 g (2 oz) icing sugar - 1 tablespoon kirsch - a pinch of cinnamon. Mix the butter with the egg, sugar, salt and lemon zest in a food processor until the mixture is smooth, then add the flour and blend in short bursts until the pastry forms a ball. Add a little flour if the mixture is sticky. ■ Leave the pastry to cool in the fridge for 30 minutes, then roll it out until it is 5 to 7 mm thick. ■ Heat the oven to 200 °C (gas mark 6 - 7). ■ Cut out shapes with a pastry cutter. ■ Place the biscuits on a baking tray covered with baking paper and spread with a mixture of the icing sugar, kirsch and cinnamon. ■ Cook in the oven for 10 minutes. ■ Dust with icing sugar to serve. Serve with a café renversé prepared with 160 ml of hot milk and a
Fortissio Lungo capsule.

MILANESE CHRISTMAS BISCUITS & FORTISSIO LUNGO CAFE RENVERSE

 ]]></page>
<page num="68"><![CDATA[
68
RÜBLITORTE CARROT CAKE & COSI
SERVES 6 PREPARATION TIME: 20 min COOKING TIME: 45 min INGREDIENTS: 6 Cosi capsules (6 x 40 ml) For the cake: 400 g (14 oz) carrots - 250 g (9 oz) ground almonds - 4 eggs -

200 g (7 oz) sugar - 60 g (2 oz) ﬂour - the zest and juice of ½ a lemon ½ sachet (1tsp) of baking powder - a pinch of salt - a knob of butter. For the icing: 1 tablespoon of kirsch - 150 g of icing sugar - 1 egg white marzipan carrot. Pre-heat the oven to 180 °C (gas mark 6). ■ Peel and grate the carrots. Separate the egg yolks and whites, then beat the yolks with the sugar until the mixture turns white. ■ Add the zest, lemon juice, grated carrots, ground almonds, flour, salt and baking powder, and blend until the mixture is smooth. ■ Beat the egg whites until stiff and stir into the mixture. ■ Grease and flour a sloping sided tin. ■ Pour the mixture into the tin and bake for around 45 minutes. ■ Check the cake is cooked by inserting the blade of a knife into the centre: it should come out clean. ■ Remove the cake from the tin and leave to cool on a cooling rack. ■ For the icing, mix the kirsch with the icing sugar and an egg white and whip until smooth. ■ Spread on the cake and leave to set. ■ Decorate with the marzipan carrot.
■

Serve with a Cosi with half a teaspoon of kirsch.

RÜBLITORTE CARROT CAKE & COSI

Ritual Espresso cup (Nespresso - design by Andrée Putman). The misuse of alcohol is dangerous for your health. Please drink responsibly.

 ]]></page>
<page num="69"><![CDATA[
NUSSTÖRTLI WALNUT AND HONEY TARTLETS & DULSÃO DO BRASIL
MAKES 12 TARTLETS PREPARATION TIME: 30 min COOLING TIME: 2 hrs COOKING TIME: 50 min INGREDIENTS: 1 Dulsão do Brasil capsule per person (1 x 40 ml) For the pastry: 300 g (10 ½ oz) ﬂour - 150 g (5 oz) butter - 150 g (5 oz) sugar a pinch of salt - 1 egg - icing sugar. For the ﬁlling: 300 g (10 ½ oz) sugar -

250 g (9 oz) shelled and ground walnuts (or hazelnuts) - 2 tablespoons of honey 200 ml (7 ﬂ oz) single cream. Put the flour and butter into a food processor and blend in short bursts for a few seconds. Add the sugar, salt and egg then continue to mix in short, sharp bursts until it has formed a pastry. ■ Refrigerate for 2 hours. ■ Flour a work surface and roll out the pastry. Cut out circles and place them in greased, floured tartlet moulds, prick with a fork and refrigerate again with the rest of the pastry. ■ Heat the sugar with 4 tablespoons of water to form a golden caramel. ■ Take off the heat and add the walnuts, honey and cream, then return to a low heat for around 10 minutes, stirring continuously, allowing the mixture to thicken a little. ■ Leave to cool, then divide the mixture between the tartlets. ■ Roll out the rest of the pastry and cut into circles to top the tartlets. Pinch the edges so that they hold together and cook in the oven for around 40 minutes. ■ Dust the tarlets with icing sugar.
Serve with a Dulsão do Brasil.

NUSSTÖRTLI WALNUT AND HONEY TARTLETS & DULSÃO DO BRASIL

 ]]></page>
<page num="70"><![CDATA[
70

CHESTNUT VERMICELLI & DECAFFEINATO INTENSO
SERVES 6 - PREPARATION TIME: 30 min COOKING TIME: 1 hr the previous day COOLING TIME: 12 hrs + 1 hr INGREDIENTS: 6 Decaffeinato Intenso capsules (6 x 40 ml) For the ﬁlling: 300 g (10 ½ oz) chestnut cream - 300 g (10 ½ oz ) chestnut purée

- 100 g (3 ½ oz) soft butter - 2 tablespoons of rum.
For the meringue: 2 egg whites - 80 g (3 oz) caster sugar 40 g (1 ½ oz) icing sugar. For the whipped cream: 300 ml single cream - 50 g (2 oz) mascarpone - seeds

from one vanilla pod - 40 g (1 ½ oz) icing sugar. Pre-heat the oven to 120 °C (gas mark 4) and cover a baking tray with baking paper. ■ Beat the egg whites until stiff, sift the caster sugar and the icing sugar and fold into the egg whites. ■ Using a piping bag with a 1 cm nozzle, squeeze the mixture into cones and bake for one hour. Lower the temperature to 100-110 °C if the meringues are browning too quickly. ■ Switch off the oven and leave the meringues in to cool for 12 hours, with the oven door ajar. In a food processor, blend the butter, chestnut cream and purée, and the rum. Place in the fridge for 12 hours. ■ Whip the cream with the vanilla seeds, mascarpone and icing sugar, and place in the fridge for one hour. ■ Open the meringues and fill with the chestnut mixture using a piping bag, then add the whipped cream. Serve with
a Decaffeinato Intenso.

CARAC CHOCOLATE TARTLETS & ARPEGGIO
photo page 66
SERVES 6 - PREPARATION TIME: 30 min COOKING TIME: 20 min COOLING TIME: at least 6 hrs INGREDIENTS: 6 Arpeggio capsules (6 x 25 ml) For the ﬁlling:

300 g (10 ½ oz) of 70 % dark chocolate, chopped - 2 Arpeggio capsules (2 x 25 ml) - 300 ml (10 ½ ﬂ oz) whipping cream - 30 g (1 oz) butter - 200 g (7 oz) icing sugar - a few drops of green food colouring. For the pastry: 350 g (12 oz) ﬂour - 250 g (9 oz) butter - 125 g (4 ½ oz) sugar - 1 teaspoon vanilla powder - 2 egg yolks.

Using a food processor, blend all the pastry ingredients except the egg yolks in short bursts. ■ When the mixture has reached a breadcrumb consistency, add the egg yolks, blend until it has formed a ball and refrigerate for two hours. ■ Turn the oven on to 180 °C (gas mark 6). ■ Roll out the pastry, cut into circles and place them in a greased tartlet tray. ■ Prick with a fork, cover in baking paper and fill with dry beans. Blind bake for 20 minutes. ■ Boil the cream. ■ Take off the heat and mix into the chopped chocolate. ■ Add the coffee and butter and leave to cool. ■ Pour this mixture into the pastry bases, but keep back a few drops. ■ Leave in the fridge for 2-3 hours. ■ Heat the icing sugar with 3 tablespoons of water and the food colouring for 2 minutes. ■ Leave to cool. Pour into the caracs. ■ Top with chocolate and refrigerate for at least 2 hours. Serve with an Arpeggio.

Glass Lungo cup (Nespresso). Ritual Cappuccino cup (Nespresso - design by Andrée Putman). The misuse of alcohol is dangerous for your health. Please drink responsibly.

 ]]></page>
<page num="71"><![CDATA[
LÄCKERLI GINGERBREAD WITH A SUGAR GLAZE & CAPPUCCINO INDRIYA FROM INDIA
MAKES 20 PIECES PREPARATION TIME: 20 min COOKING TIME: 20 min COOLING TIME: 1 hr INGREDIENTS: 1 Indriya from India capsule per person (1 x 40 ml) For the gingerbread: 2 tablespoons of mixed spice (aniseed, ginger, star anise,

cinnamon) - 125 g (4 ½ oz) sugar - 200 g (7 oz) honey - 125 g (4 ½ oz) ground almonds - 20 g (¾ oz) candied orange peel - 20 g (¾ oz) candied lemon peel 1 lemon - 80 ml (3 ﬂ oz) kirsch - 300 g (10 ½ oz) ﬂour - 1 teaspoon of baking powder. For the icing: 200 g (7 oz) icing sugar - 3 teaspoons of kirsch 1 teaspoon of water. Heat the honey in a pan over low heat. Add the sugar, spices, chopped lemon and orange peel, grated lemon zest and the kirsch. ■ Measure the almonds, flour and baking powder into a food processor, add the contents of the saucepan and blend in short bursts to form a dough. ■ Using the tips of your fingers, spread the dough in a rectangular tin lined with baking paper to a depth of 1.5 cm and place in the fridge for one hour. ■ Heat the oven to 180 °C (gas mark 6) and bake for 20 minutes. ■ Mix all the icing ingredients and pour over the cooked cake while still hot, then cut into squares.
Serve with a cappuccino made with an Indriya from India.

LÄCKERLI GINGERBREAD WITH A SUGAR GLAZE & CAPPUCCINO INDRIYA FROM INDIA

 ]]></page>
<page num="72"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="73"><![CDATA[
HISTORY An Extraordinary Story

73

LADY DADA
Text Julien Bouré

ZUR CH

In February 1916 at 1, Spiegelgasse, contemporary art was being invented in a literary café. Its name w a s C a b a r e t Vo l t a i r e .

IT ALL STARTED ON A STREET CALLED THE SPIEGELGASSE IN ZURICH. IT WAS LATE WINTER 1916 AND EUROPE’S YOUTH WAS BEING SWALLOWED UP IN THE TRENCHES AND THE BATTLE OF VERDUN ALONE WAS TO CLAIM MORE LIVES THAT THE PREVIOUS FRANCO-PRUSSIAN WAR. However, in the heights of the Alps, far from

the cataclysmic events below, the future was unfolding in a winding alley of an old alpine city. At 14 Spiegelgasse, a diminutive Russian agitator going by the name of Lenin was writing his last pamphlet before returning home to kick off the 20th century with a revolution that promised a brighter future. 100 metres down the street, at 1 Spiegelgasse, a small band of European agitators were inaugurating the 20th century in their own way, by founding the “dada” literary and artistic movement. In their respective ﬁelds, they were each setting out to wipe away a worn out, discredited past. LENIN’S TIME IN ZURICH was the story of a man of action waiting impatiently for his time to come. The story of the Dadaists, on the other hand, is much more interesting in the telling. For six months, the jolly band celebrated the overthrow of traditional aesthetics, before being forced to shut up shop for disturbing the peace. But the few weeks of Babel-like pandemonium, a strange parody on the orgy of death taking place on Switzerland’s doorstep, were enough to generate the creative chaos that has energised the arts ever since. THE MYTH IS WELL KNOWN. A select bunch of artists from all corners of the Old Continent came together from café to café, seeking refuge from the surveillance of the authorities, who wanted to keep their tranquil haven as quiet as ever. These as-yet unknown ﬁgures (which included Romanian Tristan Tzara and German Hugo Ball) ended up renting a disused city-centre bistro to create a literary café and shake up the scene, which at the time was dominated by the kind of philosophical tea parties that have now usurped the name. Even with the café’s name, they set out to shock, juxtaposing a shameful word with the name of a literary

ﬁgurehead. Thus the Cabaret Voltaire was born, with a sense of revolt that merrily praised the beauty of a porcelain urinal, and proclaimed an African tribal mask to be superior to a painting by a Western master. THE COQUETTISH DECOR included futurist, cubist and expressionist art around the walls, on loan from friends such as Modigliani, Picasso, Kandinsky or Matisse. From its opening night on 5 February 1916, Cabaret Voltaire presented the very latest musical and poetic works in front of an audience of future artists – at a time when bourgeois establishments had long since shut up shop. The unassuming appearance of this tiny venue, which held barely more than ﬁfty spectators in one sitting, did not prevent it becoming a rallying point for a generation that was to birth a whole new world of art. When the creators started to realise that Cabaret Voltaire was touching such a range of disparate and dispersed artists, they decided to write a manifesto. The title was found by opening a dictionary at random, and pointing to a word – “dada” was chosen. It was rather like a hopeful traveller planning his next trip by spinning a globe and stumbling across Chaco Boreal or the Sandwich Islands. BUT THEN THE MOVEMENT TOOK OFF. Once the war was over, it moved from country to country, drawing a moustache on the Mona Lisa or the sound holes of a violin on the shapely back of a muse. The Dada movement used incredibly efﬁcient means to deconstruct the vanity of art through the shocking juxtapositions of its collages, its cheeky bicycle-wheel sculptures or the drunken cacophony of its poems. Ridicule was the seemingly insigniﬁcant but ultimately lethal weapon that was mercilessly trained on the decency of the establishment. THE CABARET VOLTAIRE itself was shut down in the heat of summer in 1916, but opened again after an interlude as a discotheque. Later it was threatened with an incongruous future as luxury apartments. However, the local authority stepped in to pay the rent and the owner of Swatch now sponsors a “House of Dada” with events by an art collective. Nearly a century after shutting it down, the city of Zurich is now the ofﬁcial protector of this absinth-fuelled café-concert venue. Behind the puritanical appearance, a Lady Dada is alive and well inside. ■

Illustration : Mac Nooland

 ]]></page>
<page num="74"><![CDATA[
SWISS CHOCOLATE
Text Julien Bouré Photography
Jean-Claude Amiel
OPEN AN ATLAS AND TRACE THE LINES OF THE 15TH PARALLEL NORTH AND SOUTH OF THE EQUATOR. THIS NARROW BELT, WHICH BARELY COVERS A SIXTH OF THE EARTH’S SURFACE, IS THE HOME OF THE COCOA TREE.

The countries in the northernmost reaches of this zone include Mexico, Senegal, Yemen and the Philippines. Switzerland is over 2,000 miles too far north to grow cocoa. And yet the Swiss are the world’s top consumers, eating 12 kg of chocolate per capita, or more than twice as much as an American citizen eats in a year. Three of the seven largest chocolate producers have their headquarters in Switzerland, and it is also here that the industry first appeared. So the obvious question is ‘Why?’: What brought chocolate-making to this country of mountains and dairy herds, which has never administered tropical colonies? The Swiss Confederation is a country proud of its independence, be it in diplomatic, military, watch-, knife- or chocolate-making terms. It should not come as a surprise then that this country invented, and sometimes imitated, most of the ingenious food products on the market. The list of “Swiss made” original creations includes yeast extract spreads, soda stream, tubes of liver pâté, an energy bar made of malted barley which dissolves in water, yellow salt, iced tea and instant coffee. When it comes to chocolate, the range is just as exotic. What is more, there is no need to be a cocoaproducing nation in order to make chocolate. Unlike grapes, which need to be made into wine straight after harvesting, the bean undergoes a stabilising treatment similar to that of coffee. Long before the invention of refrigeration ships it could thus patiently endure the slow pace of centuries-old wind-powered sea travel. Furthermore, the production of chocolate from cocoa requires significant capital investment:

NO NEED TO BE A COCOAPRODUCING N AT I O N T O M A K E C H O C O L AT E

as with sugar, it must be processed. That is why between the farmer who gathers the pods (who might never have tasted a bar of chocolate in his life) and the chocolate maker who creates ganaches, pralines, truffles and filled sweets, there is the processor, who uses the cocoa beans to make chocolate bars. It so happened that this particular role ripened to maturity in Switzerland. The important conching process, which thins the cocoa mass, was finetuned by Rodolphe Lindt in 1879, while at the same time Daniel Peter, a businessman from Vaud, began diluting his chocolate with the milk produced in abundance on the shores of Lake Geneva. Until then, no one had dared change the original recipe of the inventors of chocolate. The Mexican natives, who gave the recipe to their Spanish occupiers, had only ever come across their mothers’ milk (cows, goats and ewes came to the New World with the conquistadors) and thus had only ever made chocolate with water. Finally, it was Henri Nestlé who invented white chocolate when he found a way to make use of the excess cocoa butter. But the most significant advance was probably that of François-Louis Cailler, who developed the first mechanical chocolate factory at the beginning of the 19th century. The nation owes the existence of its favourite sweets to this Swiss Willy Wonka: the Cailler Branches, chocolate sticks covered in hazelnut; the extra fine Frigor chocolate; the Rayon, with its crunchy honey nuggets. Now in the 21st century Nespresso has reinvented the taste sensation with its range, Les Chocolats*, specially created to subtly complement the notes of its Grands Crus. n *Only available in some countries.

How did this nation of dairy farmers become a nation of c h o c o l a t e m a k e r s ? I t i s h e r e t h a t , i n a c o n f e c t i o n e r ’s love match, milk and cocoa were brought together to make bars worth their weight in gold.

 ]]></page>
<page num="75"><![CDATA[
CULT Object

75

 ]]></page>
<page num="76"><![CDATA[
76

GRANDS CRUS Hawaii Kona

IN THE BEGINNING GINN WAS PARADISE

The elixir that ﬂows in Hawaii like a rejuvenating spring is the source of its Eden-like youthfulness. This Big Island is indebted to lava ﬂows for its heavenly coffee: the taste of paradise coveted the world over. Nespresso is devoting a Special Reserve called Hawaii Kona to this exclusive crop.
Photography Olivier Gachen Text Julien Bouré

 ]]></page>
<page num="77"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="78"><![CDATA[
AMERICAN ESPRESSO

A WRINKLE IN THE WATER, LIKE A THOUGHTFUL FROWN ON THE SMOOTH BROW OF THE PACIFIC. FROM THE AIR, HAWAII’S LARGEST ISLAND SEEMS LOST IN REVERIE, A PEACEFUL AND TENDER LAND OF FIRE THAT DREAMS OF A PAST LIFE IN THE DEPTHS OF THE OCEAN.

The lava of two active volcanoes flows quietly, drawing up its source of eternal youth from the freshest layers of the earth’s mantle, and constantly renewing the island’s basalt surface. This rugged outcrop is shaped with roads as smooth as leather straps, a lunar landscape formed from the colours of fresh tarmac blending into the volcanic rock. Drive on them and you feel the warmth emanating from this newborn soil, such is the sense that the Hawaiian archipelago, so recently emerged from the womb of the earth, is the newest that the New World has to offer. It is as if this place is still in the confusion of the unborn child, full of the promise of life to come. As though Creation was meeting in plenary session to debate the identity of the child’s father. For this peacefully tumultuous land is something of an eclectic mix: volcanic mountains, cracked deserts, rolling hills, vast prairies, poisonous jungles, active lava fields, impassable glaciers. Even surfing, the dangerous game of Hawaii’s original inhabitants, bears witness to this basic lack of inhibition as surfers soar on humungous waves which rise on the curve of the horizon.

THE MIRACLE OF “KONA” WAS ALREADY H I G H LY P R I Z E D BY NINETEENTH CENTURY CONNOISSEURS.

One of the world’s most precious coffees – and the only one grown in the United States – owes its existence to this unruly island. The name “Kona”, which is also the name of the area it comes from, means “under the wind”. Harvested in the lee of the trade winds on the western coast of the largest island in the Hawaiian archipelago, this rare coffee, “with notes of freshly ground sky”, comes from one of the scarcest varieties in the world. The island is a little smaller than Jamaica – it only takes four hours to go round it in a car – and has only 2000 acres of coffee plants across several hundred farms, most of which are family-owned. As these growers prepare to commemorate two hundred years since the little tree was introduced to the archipelago, Nespresso has decided to celebrate this miraculous coffee by dedicating a limited – by necessity – collector’s edition to it. “Kona” was already highly prized by nineteenth century connoisseurs. Tom Greenwell, undisputed patriarch of the island’s coffee-growers, proudly displays a certificate of excellence above his desk which was awarded to his great-grandfather at the Universal Exposition of 1873 in Vienna. And the Austrians really know their coffee: it was they who introduced Europeans to this mysterious commodity, found in the luggage of a sultan defeated outside their capital. According to the owner of the Greenwell farm, the incredible quality of Hawaiian crus can be explained by a number of perfectly synchronised coincidences. First of all there is the youth of this soil dotted with volcanic rocks, producing a good, dark, loose earth which is porous and nutritious – perfect for coffee plant roots, and containing sufficient nitrogen to protect against potential diseases. The atmosphere is just as important. It is conditioned by the island’s five mountain peaks, some of which are volcanically active, and all dominated by Mauna Kea, a colossus which would outstrip Everest by half a mile if measured from its base at the sea bed. Clouds arriving from other skies are left hanging as though from a peg before this unforeseen titan, forming a vast, celestial cover against the blazing heat of a tropical day. Contrary to the popular belief that Hawaii’s Big Island is an eternally sunny paradise, its glorious •••

Whether riding the ocean or the lava, Hawaiians frequently brave a sometimes ferocious nature: it makes victory all the more satisfying.

SURFING THE ELEMENTS

 ]]></page>
<page num="79"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="80"><![CDATA[
 ]]></page>
<page num="81"><![CDATA[
81
FORCE OF NATURE

The only coffee grown in the United States perfectly encapsulates the exuberant character of its homeland: an island no bigger than Jamaica, yet it fosters all the landscapes of a continent.

A RARE PEARL IN THE PACIFIC

mornings invariably give way to melancholy afternoons, the air sparkling with fine rain like soda water. This hydrating screen perfectly regulates the climate, providing optimum conditions for coffee plant photosynthesis. Finally, local varieties have not changed since they arrived on the islands in 1813. The elegant fruit of Arabica Typica, for example, which produces a clear, smooth coffee, is particularly prone to infection. Here, 3,850 km from its first shores, in damp isolation, the same crop has lit upon a blessed sanctuary. While its American cousins grown in Brazil, Colombia or Guatemala were “improved” to make them more resistant, but at the expense of their distinctive aroma, Hawaii’s isolation put it beyond the reach of pests. The crop could be maintained in virginal purity in a state of untainted innocence.
ALOHA

Kona coffee flourishes on the western side of the largest island in the Hawaiian archipelago. The area barely exceeds 2000 acres and is a miraculous pinprick in the immense Pacific Ocean, possessing all the necessary conditions for this priceless fruit to grow. Its scarcity means that some distributors dilute a tiny portion of the sought-after bean in a much greater volume of ordinary coffee. Nespresso guarantees a “pure origin” coffee, which is why this Special Reserve is such a limited edition. To ensure that every cup truly displays its incredible qualities, our Experts only select the largest, best quality beans, and make sure that they are kept in their protective “parchment” until the very last moment. The bean is then roasted to achieve a perfectly even dark caramel colour, then ground to “medium” grade. These two operations determine the quality of the coffee in your cup: constant vigilance is required to ensure that the most delicate flavours are locked in and to prevent any bitter nuances from developing.

The overseer of the Greenwell farm, “Pepe” Miranda, speaks of the difficulty of harvesting on the slopes of a volcano which are too steep for machinery. Plots are harvested by hand, and the workers are only to pick ripe fruit, just as the red pulp begins to turn crimson. During the season, which lasts from August to January, the same tree might be harvested around ten times. The coffee is then subjected to the wet process: after depulping, it is washed in fresh water then dried in the sun on traditional racks with removable canopies, named “hoshidanas” by their Japanese inventors. These Japanese pioneers were as much gardeners as farmers and had a profound influence on the development of the coffee tree around Kona. At the beginning of the last century, they committed to working on the Hawaiian sugar plantations for three years to pay for their passage to Brazil, where they hoped for a small patch of land. A few chose to stay indefinitely alongside other settlers arriving from around the world: from the Philippines, Portugal, then later from Panama, Columbia and Micronesia... Here, as anywhere in the United States, labour is expensive: where a worker in El Salvador might be paid 8 dollars for a day’s work, the going rate is 10 dollars an hour in Hawaii. But Kona coffee producers have managed to protect themselves against global competition by emphasising the unique nature of their coffee. This is achieved through meticulous agricultural practices which, at first glance, seem excessive: whether that be the green harvest (when some of the cherries are removed from the tree so that the remaining fruit has more taste), or maintaining plants between rows of coffee trees, to stimulate water stress. Sharon Wood, owner of the Arianna plantation, comments: “Every little step matters, from the early cuttings to our warehousing practices. One tiny mistake, and a year’s work is lost, collapsing like a house of cards.” She and her husband got into growing this

ONE TINY M I S TA K E , AND A YEAR’S W O R K I S L O S T, COLLAPSING LIKE A HOUSE OF CARDS.

beautiful bean after they fell in love with it during their honeymoon. The couple, who hail from California, bought 40 acres on the fertile slopes of the volcano Hualalai, and named it after their only daughter, as if to ward against failure in this crazy venture. To recreate the flavours which first drew them in, “a bouquet of fruity aromas with subtle, nutty notes,” Sharon reveals she followed the advice of more experienced farmers. Hawaiian producers are happy to share their secrets, because of the “aloha” spirit which gives the 50th American state its name. It is an untranslatable word which expresses the sunny disposition and gracious, kind nature of the inhabitants of this string of lost islands... That incredible goodwill evoked by the melodious murmur of the ukulele, smooth and predictable as a sea of glass. Sharon adds, “Kona isn’t simply a coffee paradise, it’s also heaven for those who grow it.” n

 ]]></page>
<page num="82"><![CDATA[
U has a soft spot for the 16 Grands Crus in the Nespresso range.

Love match

Nespresso’s latest machine, , does more than just blend in. It is so easy to use that it immediately becomes part of your daily life.
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

 ]]></page>
<page num="83"><![CDATA[
CYBER Café

83

The anti-drip system guarantees a spill-free coffee and the magnetic base can be removed, easily leaving space for a Recipe glass.

No spills

 ]]></page>
<page num="84"><![CDATA[
STRIPPED DOWN BEAUTY FOR AN EASY-TO-USE MACHINE

U can be customised and tailored to your tastes with its storage compartments that attach to the machine by magnet. They can be used to store capsules, spoons, sugar, or whatever you want!

 ]]></page>
<page num="85"><![CDATA[
85

Three different cup sizes at your fingertips.

Coffee as you like it

The water tray can be fitted on the left or right, to adapt to your countertop.

Slim styling

Environmentallyfriendly
U turns itself off automatically, saving more energy.

Elegant and simple colours: cream, black, orange or grey.

Total discretion

U remembers your preferences and ejects used capsules by itself.

It really understands you!

SCAN THIS CODE WITH YOUR SMARTPHONE AND DISCOVER THE WORLD OF THE U MACHINE.

 ]]></page>
<page num="86"><![CDATA[
86

EXPERTS The Collections

PRÊT-ÀPORTER
Production Sandrine Giacobetti Photography Jean-Claude Amiel

Lovers of Nespresso Grands Crus, did you know that we have designed coffee accessories with you in mind? With ﬁve quality Collections to choose from, which most reﬂects who you are?

 ]]></page>
<page num="87"><![CDATA[
1 GLASS COLLECTION

87

1 GLASS COLLECTION: TRANSPARENT MASTERPIECES

This Collection doesn’t draw attention to itself. The container vanishes and gives centre stage to the contents, making your coffee moment a visual as well as a sensual pleasure. Nespresso gives a beautiful performance in these transparent espresso, lungo and cappuccino cups. The sight of a coffee crema and ebony liquid on a charcoal coaster is pure delight.

 ]]></page>
<page num="88"><![CDATA[
88

2 CITIZ COLLECTION

 ]]></page>
<page num="89"><![CDATA[
3 RITUAL COLLECTION

89

THESE BLOWN GLASS C U P S C R E AT E A N OPTICAL ILLUSION.
2 CITIZ COLLECTION: RELAXED CITY SLICKER

As clear as the Glass Collection, these blown glass cups create an optical illusion. The clear double wall which keeps the heat of the contents away from the surface makes it look like the coffee is floating. Their spiral contours are inspired by the geometric architecture of 1930s Chicago, and they come in espresso and lungo formats. Recipe glasses and a modular tray complete the Collection, and your every whim is catered to by its range of sizes.
3 RITUAL COLLECTION: THE ART OF DRINKING COFFEE

If your coffee break is almost a religious rite, this Collection brings together the divine purity of clean lines and the expert precision of each coffee accessory. Five sizes of porcelain cups bring out the specific aromas of each type of coffee: ristretto, espresso, lungo, cappuccino and mug. Recipe glasses and water glasses accompany the ritual, and there are spoons specially designed to touch - but not break - the crema. These accessories embrace the straight yet rounded silhouette of Nespresso capsules and the same sobriety is found in the Barista kit which completes the range, including a shaker, milk jug and chocolate sprinkler.

 ]]></page>
<page num="90"><![CDATA[
90

4 PIXIE COLLECTION

Y O U R TA B L E I S TRANSFORMED I N T O A T H E AT R I C A L PERFORMANCE, A S O P H I S T I C AT E D , S U R P R I S I N G P L AY.

4 PIXIE COLLECTION: ICONIC AND PLAYFUL

This collection is for those who see coffee as carefree relaxation, a pleasure to be enjoyed anytime, anywhere. For such as these, Nespresso has designed stainless steel cups, whose double wall guarantees excellent heat insulation. Their smooth surface evokes Nespresso capsules, as do the sixteen colours available which embody the variety of the range of Grands Crus and throw up combination possibilities as playful as the spirit of this Collection.
5 PREMIUM COLLECTION: JEWELLER’S INSPIRATION

Your table is transformed into a theatrical performance, a sophisticated, surprising play combining relaxed elegance and quiet impudence. The ancient knowledge of the great masters of porcelain and crystal come together in these jewel-like espresso cups. With their matte gold accents, these luxury cases are the height of delicacy, paying homage to the perfection of our Grands Crus.
CAFÉ ABSOLU CANDLE: THE SCENT OF TRAVEL

Nespresso looked to the biggest name in the world of perfume, Olivia Giavobetti, to prolong the intensity of your coffee moments. She designed the Café Absolu candle, a special harmony of absolute coffee, with notes of precious wood, cocoa beans and Bourbon vanilla. An invitation to an olfactory journey, and the essence of Nespresso’s coffee ideal.

 ]]></page>
<page num="91"><![CDATA[
5 PREMIUM COLLECTION

91

FIND ALL THE COLLECTIONS AT WWW.NESPRESSO.COM

 ]]></page>
<page num="92"><![CDATA[
92

 ]]></page>
<page num="93"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO Recycling
Text Francis Dolric Photography
Jean-Claude Amiel
IN THE 1860S, THE THREE HEROES OF JULES VERNE’S “FROM THE EARTH TO THE MOON”TRAVELLED THROUGH SPACE ABOARD A VESSEL MADE OF A METAL THAT IS STRONG, LIGHT, AIRTIGHT, EASY TO FASHION, KEEPS ITS SHAPE AND DOES NOT OXIDISE: ALUMINIUM. Back

93

Over the last twenty years, Nespresso has paid serious attention to environmental issues. The aluminium capsule is unrivalled when it comes to protecting your Grands C r u s b u t i t i s a l s o e n v i r o n m e n t a l l y - f r i e n d l y : u s i n g m i n i m a l e n e r g y, t h i s m e t a l c a n b e m a d e t o l a s t f o r e v e r, s o N e s p r e s s o m a k e s s u r e i t i s b r o u g h t b a c k t o l i f e .

then, aluminium was already seen as the manufacturing solution of the future: compared to an equal weight of steel, it is twice as strong. But due to production costs, it was considered a precious metal: during a banquet given by Napoleon III, honoured guests ate off an aluminium dinner service while the others had to make do with mere gold. If the visionary novelist were to stumble across a Nespresso capsule today, a century and a half later, he would see in it the qualities of his space vessel, such as air-tightness and protection. “To get the best results, the ground coffee must be protected from oxygen, moisture and light,” explains Alexis Rodriguez, the Nespresso Coffee Expert who bestows Grands Crus and Limited Editions with the sensational aroma that must be protected until the moment the coffee is drunk. “Aluminium offers ideal protection against this triple threat.” In short, the Nespresso capsule is both a container and a suit of armour. Aside from its ability to preserve ﬂavours intact, Nespresso has also taken advantage of aluminium’s incredible recycling potential for over twenty years. Simply melting down recovered fragments is enough to restore the properties of the original metal. This recycling process also uses very little energy: only 5% of the energy required to extract the same quantity of metal. Such great beneﬁts meant that Nespresso prioritised the implementation of a speciﬁc procedure.
A CHRONICLE OF COLLECTION

And so it was in Switzerland, the home of Nespresso and a country particularly interested in environmental issues, that capsule recycling began in 1989, alongside the launch of the ﬁrst range of domestic machines. Marc-Alain Dubois, who is currently European Commercial Director at Nespresso, was at the helm of the Swiss market at the time. He recalls, “The trifold business model of machine, capsule and club had been established. But creating a recycling system seemed a Herculean task. Where would Nespresso Club Members dispose of used capsules? What process would separate coffee grounds from the aluminium? Finally, how could we persuade Nespresso Club Members to recycle their capsules rather than throw them out? At the time, people hadn’t got used to the idea of portioned coffee.” They came up straightaway with a rule, which is still kept to: Nespresso would invest in the best solutions... Club Members had the right to choose. No one would be forced to recycle. In 1990, at a time when there was still no real provision for recycling, Nespresso came up with their ﬁrst collection method: an empty recycling bag came with each order, which could be returned to Nespresso ﬁlled with used capsules. This idea has in fact stayed the course, since a current version of the system, called “Recycling at Home” is proving successful in the

Swiss cantons. “At the time, we contacted a Swiss aluminium collecting cooperative called Igora,” MarcAlain Dubois continues, “but they were unable to separate the coffee grounds from the aluminium. Finally, it was Thévenaz-Leduc, a group which specialises in recycling metals, that allowed us to use their 35 collection points.” Collection points are the strategic heart of the whole operation, he explains. “We immediately realised the great importance of giving the consumer easy access to the network. This need was met when we were able to install handy collection points in shops where machines were sold, then in Nespresso Boutiques as they opened. The ﬁrst of these, found on the Loewenstrasse in Zurich, is still running! Swiss towns then suggested specialised containers. The increasing number of collection points in Switzerland created a need for a more comprehensive recycling solution. You could describe it as a virtuous circle.”
THE IMPORTANCE OF NETWORKS

How has capsule recycling evolved since the introduction of the ﬁrst Nespresso machines? The ﬁrst change is quantitative. A number of other countries which have fallen in love with Nespresso Grands Crus have gradually signed up to the associated recycling solutions. The ﬁrst recycling schemes in other countries may only have appeared ten years after they were initiated in Switzerland, but there are now 20,000 collection points available to Nespresso Club Members across the globe. And the number is growing with each passing month. The aim of being able to recycle 75% of capsules by 2013 has already been ••• reached.

 ]]></page>
<page num="94"><![CDATA[
94
The second change is logistical. Nespresso now works in line with recycling systems in individual countries. Depending on local conditions, collection points can be found not only in Nespresso Boutiques but also in shops which sell our machines, recycling centres with specialised containers and in shops where products bought online can be collected. The increasing number and diversity of collection points demonstrate both our commitment to making Nespresso Club Members’ lives simpler and providing a personal service which beneﬁts everyone.
REMAINING CHALLENGES

A second collection method, which makes use of national waste collection systems, is also being closely monitored. The method is already in place in Germany, Switzerland and Finland: used capsules are thrown in recycling bins for packaging, often found in the bottom of apartment blocks. And others are following suit. In the south of France, Nespresso has introduced an initiative which means capsules can be thrown in the “yellow bin” – the one which is then sorted – in apartment blocks. At the sorting centre, a hightech piece of equipment removes them and injects them into the recycling system. This makes recycling easier for the consumer and thus guarantees a higher recuperation rate. Whether methods are individual or communal, and no matter what systems are used, one great principle is central: each country comes up with its own scheme. Removing coffee grounds from the aluminium is more a technical than logistical challenge, met in 1990 with a crushing system which has since beneﬁtted from regular improvements. In this area too, the choice of solution is always left up to regional subsidiaries. In the South, old capsules are left outside to dry: using the sun’s energy doesn’t cost the earth! Elsewhere, heating or washing is used. Coffee grounds are used as organic fertilizer or as a source of green energy. And the aluminium is made ready for its next reincarnation. Quite simply, they are given a new lease of life... and it’s all up to you.
EVERY LITTLE HELPS

More collection points than ever, researching the best ways to remove coffee grounds from the metal, integrating used capsules into recycling collection systems... for over twenty years, Nespresso has been investing its time, money and intelligence into ﬁnding the best solutions. Why? Because we, like many others, believe that recycling is worth the investment, and that with the cooperation of Nespresso Club Members, our capsules can be given new life. Every little gesture helps build our future. There are more than 20,000 collection points around the world. Find your nearest one using our geolocalisation system at www.nespresso.com/ecolaboration, or via the Nespresso mobile app.

PIXIE RECYCLING AMBASSADOR
What is the point of recycling capsules? The answer can be found simply by popping into your nearest Nespresso Boutique. Because the PIXIE machine’s elegant casing is actually made out of millions of used capsules which have been recycled by Nespresso Club Members! Its new coloured side panels – available in Carmine or Brown – are made from 98% Nespresso capsules which have been recycled in Switzerland! There is no better way to walk the walk: the cute PIXIE machine, which was already energy efficient, is now a real-life illustration of the benefits of collecting capsules. A recycling ambassador able to reach out to coffee lovers around the world, with no need for an interpreter.
> www.nespresso.com/ecolaboration

 ]]></page>
<page num="95"><![CDATA[
95

RECYCLING IN FOUR STEPS
This photo story was shot at the Papirec factory (part of the Thévenaz-Leduc group) in Moudon, Switzerland. The factory is contracted by Nespresso to recycle capsules. The process has three steps: storage of used capsules, separation of coffee grounds from the aluminium and compacting of the two materials. A fourth step, melting down the aluminium, takes place at another factory.

 ]]></page>
<page num="96"><![CDATA[
96

For over twenty-five years, the Rainforest Alliance has managed to create a chain of international cooperation to support tropical forests and their inhabitants. The key tool for this NGO is a label for farms that have been trained in implementing sustainable agriculture and producing quality coffee, in line with the Nespresso AAA Sustainable Q u a l i t y TM P r o g r a m m e .
Text by Nadia Hamam Photographs by Olivier Gachen and Maggie Lear

WHY AND HOW DID YOU SET UP RAINFOREST ALLIANCE? D. K. When I graduated from college in 1984, my friends and

I realised how unaware the public was about deforestation taking place in tropical forests: ﬂora and fauna in danger, indigenous communities with no voice to defend themselves, and so on. In New York in 1987 we coordinated the ﬁrst global conference on the present state and the future hopes for conserving endangered tropical forests... Around ﬁfty speakers, including government representatives and company leaders, spoke to seven hundred audience members about one issue: What solutions must we implement to protect this biodiversity and humanity in danger? Shortly after the conference we started developing programs, including the certification of forests, agricultural lands and tourism. Our persistence and passion allowed us to overcome every obstacle. Since then, this strong will has become the signature of Rainforest Alliance: a philosophy of action.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN WORKING WITH NESPRESSO? D. K. We decided to work together in 2003, on the develop-

the farming practices themselves: we work with producers who opt for a sustainable model. When these coffee farmers are ready, their parcels are awarded Rainforest Alliance certification.
WHAT DOES THE CERTIFICATION MEAN FOR COFFEE FARMERS AND HOW DO THEY OBTAIN IT? D. K. The Rainforest Alliance Certiﬁed seal guarantees

ment of the AAA Programme. This is a series of recommendations for farmers and is implemented mainly to help them produce ﬁne quality coffee while conserving the natural resources on which their farms depend, and fostering fair and balanced relationships with local communities. This strategic plan, which is unique in the world for this industry, is built on a win-win notion: it is good for the planet and for the farmers, but also for Nespresso Members, who gain access to exceptional coffee in terms of taste, ecology and ethics. This is the meaning of the Sustainable QualityTM label. Only 1 to 2% of global production achieves this quality.
AT WHAT POINT ARE YOU INVOLVED IN THIS PROCESS? D. K. While Nespresso contributes its know-how to the selec -

tion and cultivation of the best coffee, our expertise targets

that the coffee has been grown in plantations where the forest is conserved. It means that farm workers are paid decently and treated with respect, with the key element being access to education and healthcare. Farmers wishing to obtain our label must fulﬁl a certain number of conditions. In particular they must use farming techniques which respect the environment and guarantee quality coffee beans. Basically, we give the farmers a list of criteria, then we provide assistance in the long term: an advisor studies the stages in the growing process to determine which are carried out well, and which require speciﬁc attention. Soil health. Waste processing. Relations

 ]]></page>
<page num="97"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO Partner

97

DAN KATZ
AN ECOWARRIOR FOR BIODIVERSITY
“NESPRESSO CONTRIBUTES ITS KNOWH O W T O T H E C U LT I VAT I O N O F T H E B E S T C O F F E E , O U R E X P E R T I S E TA R G E T S T H E FA R M I N G P R A C T I C E S T H E M S E LV E S . ”
with farm employees. Nothing is left to chance. Once the farm is certiﬁed, we help it to reach a premium market, with a purchase price higher than conventional coffee.
WHAT ARE THE CHALLENGES IN THE FIELD? D. K. Reaching all these coffee growers, who mostly live in

with the highest needs, it is essential to build up our image in these countries, so that their people know they can work alongside us, in complete trust.
HOW IS NESPRESSO INVOLVED IN THIS PARTNERSHIP?

isolated regions, work on very small parcels of land and have limited resources. Also, explaining with persuasive language what we do, and the advantages of making the social and environmental improvements required by the program. Our goal is for them to appropriate this sustainable approach. In order to create solutions on a local scale, among the populations

D. K. Nespresso works both upstream and downstream in a powerful value chain for coffee heritage. In the ﬁeld, it focuses its effort on ensuring that most of the farms it works with are in the AAA Programme. This is a guarantee for Nespresso to develop a sustainable source of excellent coffee. In addition, we set ourselves objectives which are shared by a certain number of selected farms. Downstream, Nespresso works on informing enthusiasts about Grands Crus: good coffee that is grown according to the charter we have deﬁned together and is beneﬁcial for the environment. Wooded plantations provide buffer zones which are rich in biodiversity. This is what we call a virtuous circle. n

 ]]></page>
<page num="98"><![CDATA[
98

Nespresso Beach is a haven of tranquillity on the Croisette, where actors and directors enjoy private meals and cosy interviews. Some of them even take the opportunity to adjust their bow tie before climbing the famous steps.

 ]]></page>
<page num="99"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO Club Members

99

T H E C A N N E S F I L M F E S T I VA L I S A L S O A M E E T I N G P L A C E F O R F I L M B U F F S . A S PA R T N E R O F T H E CRITICS’ WEEK, NESPRESSO INVITED ITS MEMBERS T O D I S C O V E R N E W TA L E N T S .
Text Anna Penotti Photography Olivier Gachen and Emmanuel Nguyen Ngoc

PREMIERE
Cr iti cs ’ Week h as pre vio u s ly re w a rde d the ta le nts of Ke n Loa c h an d G u il ler m o d el To ro . T h is ye a r, the jury me t on Ne spre sso Beach to deliberate.
BEHIND THE SCENES

Nespresso beach, opening out over a sea view.
THE GLITTER, THE GLITZ AND THE STARS ARE ALL THERE OF COURSE, ALONGSIDE THE EVENING DRESSES AND YACHTS IN THE BAY. IMAGES OF MARILYN MONROE MUSE OF THE 65TH CANNES FILM FESTIVAL ARE PLASTERED OVER EVERY WALL IN THE CITY. But the reason Nespresso is an

Since last year, Nespresso has been the leading partner, awarding the “Nespresso Grand Prize for Critics’ Week” to the best feature ﬁlm in the competition. It is only natural that privileges be extended to Nespresso Club Members. A special competition for ﬁlm buffs gave several dozen Club Members the chance to enjoy behind the scenes access to the Festival, including Catherine and Pierre-Guy, from Nice. Their cinematic knowledge won them tickets to the screening of “Hors les Murs” (“Beyond the Walls”), the ﬁrst ﬁlm by Belgian producer David Lambert. It was a rare opportunity for these fans of François Truffaut to join the jury, cast and crew in the theatre – which is normally only open to a select group of professionals.
BLACK AND WHITE DÉCOR, WITH A SEA VIEW

ofﬁcial partner of the Festival for the ﬁfth year running is because of a shared pioneering spirit. It’s at Cannes that new directors are discovered and faces to grace future magazine covers are spotted. Alongside the official competition, other categories which are narrower but just as exacting focus on unveiling the next big thing.
TALENT SPOTTING

One of these selections, Critics’ Week, runs parallel with the Festival. Founded ﬁfty years ago by French cinema critics to discover new talent, it only selects ﬁrst ﬁlms by new directors, like a talent-spotting agency. This distinctive idea was bound to attract Nespresso, the “talent spotter of Grands Crus”, whose aim is always to innovate, surprise and unearth new treasures for coffee lovers.

Upon leaving the dark movie theatres, our Very Important Members returned to the Croisette and the chic black and white décor of Nespresso Beach. Comfortably seated in perfectly designed loungers, our guests were able to savour the moment and enjoy the calm of the beach. Take, for example, Julian and Oliver, two other winners from the region, who happily joined in the photo shoot between two Espressos. “You don’t get a lot of sleep at Cannes, which is why you need good coffee,” jokes one journalist, sipping his third Livanto. Dressed in a dark suit and slim-ﬁt shirt, Julian, occasional DJ, could easily pass for one of the many young actors who come to Nespresso Beach every day for interviews. A Tarantino fan, he particularly appreciates the chance to be able to discover new ﬁlms d’auteur. And the privileges don’t stop there: a top-class dinner awaits him on the beach, where the sparkling champagne will compete only with the sparkling atmosphere of a Cannes evening. Feet in the sand, head in the clouds. With Marilyn looking down from above. ■

Marilyn, icon of the 65th Cannes Film Festival. Julian and Oliver enjoying their day behind the scenes. The team from “Aquí y allá” (Here and There) by Antonio Méndez Esparza, winner of the Nespresso Grand Prize for Critics’ Week. The Nespresso Grands Crus play a starring role on the beach.

 ]]></page>
<page num="100"><![CDATA[
100

THIS RARE “PURE ORIGIN” COFFEE IS A HIDDEN GEM, PRODUCED AS A VERY LIMITED EDITION. A SPECIAL RESERVE WHICH ALSO FEATURES IN OUR PROFESSIONAL RANGE AND ON THE MENUS OF SOME OF THE WORLD’S TOP RESTAURANTS.

HAWAII KONA GOURMET COFFEE
It comes from perhaps the rarest variety in the world. Barely 2000 acres on the volcanic slopes of the island of Hawaii, where farmers who love their land grow a coffee with incomparable exuberance (see the Grands Cr us section). As it celebrates its two hundredth anniversary, Nespresso has chosen to dedicate an exclusive edition to the famous coffee, using only the best beans. The care and discipline which goes into the harvest explains why this coffee is so rare. Why does it provoke such longing among the most devoted coffee lovers? Because of its silky texture and fruity aroma complemented by subtle nutty notes. To taste an Espresso of this calibre is an unforgettable experience. Connoisseurs will be able to sample the precious Special Reserve Hawaii Kona. But you’ll have to be quick! This edition will be more limited than ever: Kona coffee accounts for less than 1% of the global harvest and Nespresso is only using its best beans. These precious capsules are sold in a box of the same silver colour as the Grand Cru itself. Each box contains two packs of Hawaii Kona and a detailed history of the rare coffee, along with a tasting tray and two Pixie cups (see photo). The perfect complement to an exceptional edition. What a delight!
A GRAND CRU COVETED BY CHEFS TOO

The Hawaii Kona is also causing a stir in professional circles. A handful of lucky chefs have already expressed their excitement about the Special Reserve. A few months ago, Nespresso organised two initiation tasting workshops bringing together the seasoned palates of master sommeliers and great chefs such as Catalan Ana Lucía Jarquin (ABaC, 2 Michelin stars), Frenchman Édouard Loubet (Domaine de Cape Longue, 2 stars) and Flemish Syrco Bakker (Syrco, 1 star). These professional tasters were able to enjoy the gastronomic potential of this Grand Cru before taking time to try marrying it with various dishes. Look out for it on the menus of some of the greatest hotels, restaurants and cafés on earth. WWW.NESPRESSO.COM/HAWAIIKONA

Collection box Contains 2 packs of Hawaii Kona capsules, two Pixie cups and mixers.
THIS BOX MAY NOT BE AVAILABLE IN YOUR COUNTRY.

Olivier Gachen - All rights reserved.

 ]]></page>
<page num="101"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO News

101

2012 VARIATIONS

NEW FLAVOURS FOR YOU TO DISCOVER
COCONUT, HAZELNUT AND MACADAMIA NUT FLAVOURS… DISCOVER THE 2012 VARIATIONS, BASED AROUND A BALANCED, LIGHTLY ROASTED LIVANTO GRAND CRU.

In an exciting end to the Nespresso year, the three all-new Variations developed by our Experts are now ready for your delectation and delight. This year they pay homage to a trio of nuts, and by extension a whole world of taste in harmony with the spirit of coffee. The first of these creations, Coconut flavour, is warm and tropical; its pairing with a Livanto Grand Cru reveals gourmet, biscuit flavours. Hazelnut flavour offers a sensual depth of taste and creates an autumnal atmosphere. When brought together with a Livanto Grand Cru, its lightly roasted nuances give way to notes of praline and a beautifully balanced taste. The third is Macadamia Nut flavour, whose sweet tones combined with the full taste of a Livanto Grand Cru creates a new

fresh savour, delicately soaked in fruity aromas. This year, the three flavour profiles all blend perfectly with milk. Combining it with notes of coconut produces a harmoniously smooth, creamy, latte macchiato. Similarly, when paired with the praline nuances of Hazelnut flavour, milk reveals the sweet, languid aromas of caramel and roasted nuts. Macadamia Nut flavour comes into its own in a cappuccino. So many flavours to be enjoyed, and no need to worry: the 2012 Variations contain zero allergenic molecules. As with all Nespresso Limited Editions, they are made only from ground coffee beans and 100% natural flavourings. These Variations are available for a limited time only. So don’t delay!
> www.nespresso.com/variations

2012 Variations This year, the Variations pay homage to a trio of nuts, best enjoyed in a latte macchiato or cappuccino.

 ]]></page>
<page num="102"><![CDATA[
102

1962 Born on 11 July in Lausanne, Switzerland. 1990 Co-invents the 3DL sail. 1999-2009 Participates in four America’s Cups, winning two: Be Happy (CH) in 2000, Alinghi (CH) in 2003, 2007 & 2009. 2010-2013 Fifth campaign as performance analyst for ETNZ.

LUC DU BOIS

LUC DU BOIS SAILING
Emirates Team New Zealand, sponsored by Nespresso, are hoping their wing-sailed catamaran will “take off” in the 34th America’s Cup. Working within the New Zealand design team, Swiss technician Luc Du Bois knows just how to help.
Text Camille El Beze Photography Chris Cameron and Francesco Ferri
NAME: LUC DU BOIS. BIRTHPLACE: LAUSANNE. PROFESSION: PERFORMANCE ANALYST FOR EMIRATES TEAM NEW ZEALAND.

tional man. He has a degree in geophysics (he studied the structure of the Alps for two years), is an Olympic racer (sailing in the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics), loves surﬁng, skiing and gliding, and most importantly, this inveterate inventor is co-creator of a technology that has revolutionised sailing around the world: the 3DL (Three-Dimensional Laminate).
FROM SWITZERLAND TO NEW ZEALAND

Mission: to gather and analyse data from dozens of experiments carried out on the water and compare them with the designers’ predictions. Working at the cutting edge of science and research requires intelligence and ability in many areas. The role suits him down to the ground. Like the legendary Swiss Army Knife, Luc du Bois is a multifaceted, multifunc-

In the late 1980s, in his parents’ basement, Luc and his friend Jean-Pierre Baudet developed this innovative process “with a good idea but little money”. The patent was sold to sailmakers North. Luc w then spend seven years in the United States developing the technology and production tools. In 1992, the ﬁrst 3DL sails were used by the Dennis Conner and the New Zealand America’s Cup teams. Thus it was on the other side of the Atlantic that Luc ﬁrst met the America’s Cup... and his future wife. From one Cup to the next, ﬁrst with Be Happy then with Alinghi, the Du Bois clan grew and became a nomadic family, living be-

 ]]></page>
<page num="103"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO Sport

103

To optimise their performance, the sailors of Emirates Team New Zealand are drawing on the knowledge of Luc Du Bois, a Swiss scientist and sailor.

DREAM
tween New Zealand, Switzerland and Spain. “My children started school in Valencia. Ryan, the youngest, speaks Spanish and English as well as he does French.” The family moved to Auckland two years ago. For Luc, who had al-

wouldn’t have missed the advent of multihull vessels in the Cup for anything. The speed of the ultra-powerful AC72s (22 m catamarans with a 40 m rigid sail) means that Archimedean forces can be partially overcome and 7 tonnes of carbon can soar above the waves. Icarus dreamt of ﬂying. Luc, along with all the design teams involved in the 34th America’s Cup, dreams of ﬂying on water.
WORKING WITH MYSTERIES

“WHAT I LOVE ABOUT SAILING IS THAT THERE ARE NO LIMITS.”
ways competed with his fellow Swiss, the Kiwi experience is new, refreshing and as exciting as ever. “They know the America’s Cup so well: they know how to get a team together and how to win. Regattas are part of their culture, like skiing in Switzerland, they love it, it is deeply engrained. Their real strength, their driving force, is motivation. Hard work is second nature to them.” Luc is passionate about A-class catamarans – small, fast, one-man boats – and

The ﬁrst large wing-sailed catamarans were launched in July 2012. The challenge for everyone will be to get them to lift off from the surface of the water and to learn how to handle them in the windy conditions of the San Francisco Bay (the competition begins on 4 July 2013). Will they succeed? Despite all the calculations, models, and reducedscale experiments, the result might not be perfect. But imperfection is all part of the game, and the paradox is what motivates Luc, who loves analysing complex phenomena with a sense of awe of their mystery. “What I love about sailing is that there are no limits. Operating at the air-water interface and with the buffeting yet unseen wind is so complicated. Nothing is static, it’s an endless conundrum. My job is to understand all that.” No doubt there are still many avenues for him to explore. ■

 ]]></page>
<page num="104"><![CDATA[
104

Machines& Collections
HIDE SOME INGENIOUS FINDS.

U AND GLASS: A MACHINE AND A COLLECTION. THESE CLEAN LINES
MADE FOR EACHOTHER!

PURE GREY

PURE BLACK

PURE ORANGE

PURE CREAM
Photos are indicative only. Nespresso reserves the right to modify products and prices without notice.

U Magnet Set Set of 2 black magnetic melamine dispensers, with 1 removable inner and a tray. The dispensers are stackable and can be magnetised to each side of the U machine. Ref. 3396/2

U Carrier Bi-coloured PVC carrier bag designed to hold 1 U machine. Ref. 3397

Totem 2 in 1 Melamine capsule dispenser. Comes in high version with four compartments for organised storage. Can easily be turned into low version for loose storage (supplied without capsules). Black and white. Ref. 3394

FIND AND ORDER ALL MACHINES & COLLECTIONS ON OUR WEBSITE: www.nespresso.com

 ]]></page>
<page num="105"><![CDATA[
NESPRESSO Selection
Glass Collection. Watching your coffee brew is a magical experience. Nespresso lets you witness this moment of pure pleasure by choosing one of our tempered glass cups. This material and its refined cone form ensure that the content remains the star of the show. The two-tone saucers add a hint of sublime colour.

105

Espresso Glass Set of 2 tempered glass Espresso cups (ca. 80 ml) and bicolour black and charcoal grey melamine saucers. Ref. 3382/2

Lungo Glass Set of 2 tempered glass Lungo cups in tempered glass (ca. 150 ml) and bicolour black and charcoal grey melamine saucers. Ref. 3383/2

Espresso and Lungo Glass Set of 2 Espresso (ca. 80 ml) and 2 Lungo (ca. 150 ml) cups in tempered glass and bicolour charcoal grey melamine saucers. Ref. 3384/4

Cappuccino Glass Set of 2 tempered glass cups (ca. 170 ml) and bicolour black and charcoal grey melamine saucers. Ref. 3390/2

Recipe Glass Set of 4 tempered-glass Recipe glasses (ca. 350 ml) and 4 stainless steel Recipe spoons (18/10). Ref. 3393/4 Glass Kit Set of 2 Espresso (ca. 80 ml) and 2 Cappuccino cups (ca. 170 ml) in tempered glass and bicolour black and white melamine saucers. Ref. 3621

Café Absolu Candle The essence of coffee, the balance of a prestigious coffee, both intense and smooth. An exclusive harmony of coffee aroma, enhanced by precious woody notes, cocoa beans and Bourbon vanilla. Ref. 3513

Bonbonnière Transparent capsule dispenser. Capacity: 50 capsules (supplied without capsules). Ref. 3395

CERTAIN ACCESSORIES MAY BE UNAVAILABLE IN YOUR COUNTRY.

 ]]></page>
<page num="106"><![CDATA[
106

NESPRESSO Contacts

24/7 SERVICE CLUBS & BOUTIQUES
NESPRESSO IS PRESENT ON EVERY CONTINENT AND IN MORE THAN 40 COUNTRIES WORLDWIDE.*
ANDORRA
Freephone number: 1 800 0259 Andorra la Vella.

PORTUGAL
Freephone number: 800 260 260 Aveiro, Braga, Coimbra, Lisbon, Porto.

Pamplona, Reus, San Sebastián, Sabadell, Santander, Seville, Tarragona, Tenerife, Terrassa, Valencia, Valladolid, Vitoria, Zaragoza.

QATAR
Freephone number: 800 08 88 Doha.

SWEDEN
Freephone number: 0200 456 600 Malmö, Stockholm.

CHINA

GREECE

ARGENTINA

Freephone number: 0800 999 0392 Buenos Aires.

Freephone number: 108 0065 00 515 (China NetCom) 108 0026 50 532 (China TeleCom) Beijing, Chengdu, Shanghai.

Tel.: 210 677 1300 Athens, Thessaloniki.

KUWAIT

Tel.: 965 249 22 600 South Surra.

REUNION
Freephone number: 0800 222 000 St-Denis, St-Pierre.

SWITZERLAND
Freephone number: 0800 55 52 53 Baden, Basel, Bern, Biel, Fribourg, Geneva, Lausanne, Lucerne, Lugano, Paudex, St. Gallen, St. Moritz, Thun, Winterthur, Zug, Zurich.

HONG KONG

Freephone number: 800 968 821 Hong Kong.

LEBANON

Tel.: 961 5 953 700 Beirut.

RUSSIA
Freephone number: 8 800 200 0004 Moscow, Saint Petersburg.

AUSTRALIA

CYPRUS

Freephone number: 1800 623 033 Adelaide, Brisbane, Chatswood, Melbourne, Perth, Robina, Sydney.

Freephone number: 80002223 Nicosia.

HUNGARY

LUXEMBOURG
Freephone number: 8002 26 33 Luxembourg.

CZECH REPUBLIC

Freephone number: 06 80 CLUB 80 (06 80 2582 80) Budapest.

MEXICO

SAUDI ARABIA
Freephone number: 800 11 666 12 Jeddah.

AUSTRIA

Freephone number: 0800 COFFEE (26 33 33) Prague.

IRELAND

Freephone number: 0800 216 251 Graz, Innsbruck, Linz, Salzburg, Vienna.

DENMARK

Freephone number: 1 800 81 26 60 Cork, Dublin.

Freephone number: 01 800 999 75 75 Mexico City.

TAIWAN

Tel.: 00 80 665 19 71 Taipei.

MOROCCO

BELGIUM

Freephone number: 80 909 600 Copenhagen.

ISRAEL

Freephone number: 0800 162 64 Antwerp, Brussels, Liege.

EGYPT

Tel.: 22 668 032 Cairo.

Freephone number: 1 800 255 355 Jerusalem, Petah Tikva, Tel-Aviv. Freephone number: 800 39 20 29 Bari, Bergamo, Bologna, Bolzano, Brescia, Catania, Como, Florence, Genoa, Milan, Modena, Naples, Padua, Rome, Treviso, Turin, Varese, Verona.

Freephone number: 08 200 1200 Casablanca.

SINGAPORE
Freephone number: 800 852 3525 Singapore.

TURKEY
Tel.: 444 1 576 Istanbul.

NETHERLANDS

ITALY

BRAZIL

FRANCE

Freephone number: 0800 7777 737 Brasilia, Belo Horizonte, Campinas, Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo.

CANADA

Freephone number: 0800 55 52 53 Bordeaux, Cannes, Grenoble, Lille, Lyon, Marseille, Mulhouse, Nantes, Nice, Paris, Paris-Orly (airport), Strasbourg, Toulon, Toulouse.

Freephone number: 0800 022 2320 Amstelveen, Amsterdam, Arnhem, Eindhoven, Maastricht, Rotterdam, The Hague, Utrecht.

SOUTH AFRICA
Freephone number: 0800 63777 3776 Cape Town, Johannesburg.

UNITED ARAB EMIRATES
Tel.: 800 NESPRESSO (63773776) Abu Dhabi, Dubai.

UNITED KINGDOM
Freephone number: 0800 442 442 Birmingham, London, Manchester.

SOUTH KOREA
Freephone number: 0807 34 11 11 Busan, Daegu, Seoul.

NEW ZEALAND
Freephone number: 0800 234 579 Auckland.

SPAIN
Freephone number: 900 259 259 Alcalá de Henares, Alicante, Barcelona, Bilbao, Castellon, Elche, Girona, La Coruña, Madrid, Malaga, Marbella, Murcia, Oviedo, Palma,

USA
Freephone number: 1 800 562 1465 Aventura, Boston, Chevy Chase, Chicago, Costa Mesa, Los Angeles, Miami, New York, San Diego, San Francisco, Scottsdale.

Freephone number: 1 800 562 1465 Edmonton, Montreal, Toronto, Vancouver.

GERMANY

JAPAN

NORWAY

CHILE

Freephone number: 800 211 222 Santiago.

Freephone number: 0800 18 18 444 Berlin, Cologne, Düsseldorf, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Hanover, Munich, Nuremberg, Stuttgart.

Freephone number: 0120 57 3101 Chiba, Fukuoka, Hiroshima, Kyoto, Nagoya, Osaka, Sapporo, Tokyo, Yokohama.

Freephone number: 800 87 600 Bergen, Oslo.

POLAND

Freephone number: 0800 51 52 53 Warsaw.

* TO FIND THE ADDRESS OF A NESPRESSO BOUTIQUE, TELEPHONE THE CLUB IN THE RELEVANT COUNTRY OR VISIT WWW.NESPRESSO.COM

BUSINESS SOLUTIONS
FOR FOR
A CUSTOMISED SOLUTION TAILORED TO YOUR COMPANY , PLEASE CONTACT YOUR LOCAL SALES ADVISOR . MORE INFO :

DENMARK Tel.: 8030 03 03 FINLAND Tel.: 0800 177 500 FRANCE Tel.: 0805 10 20 22 GERMANY Tel.: 0800 026 34 66 GREECE Tel.: 2106 71 10 07 HONG KONG Tel.: 800 905 486 HUNGARY Tel.: 0680 25 82 80 IRELAND Tel.: 1800 81 86 68

ITALY Tel.: 800 20 56 62 JAPAN Tel.: 813 4334 7040 MALAYSIA Tel.: 03 6257 1600 MEXICO Tel.: 01 800 832 46 62 NETHERLANDS Tel.: 0800 024 80 10 NORWAY Tel.: 800 87 500 POLAND Tel.: 022 837 05 57 PORTUGAL Tel.: 800 785 785

RUSSIA Tel.: 8 800 200 0039 SINGAPORE Tel.: 800 186 5007 SOUTH KOREA Tel. : 0807 341113 SPAIN Tel.: 902 11 00 20 SWEDEN Tel.: 0200 21 11 14 SWITZERLAND bj-coffee S.A. Tel.: 022 708 08 60 Lyreco A.G. Tel.: 0800 484 484

www.nespresso.com/pro
ARGENTINA Tel.: 0800 999 0394 AUSTRALIA Tel.: 1800 182 206 AUSTRIA Tel.: 0810 981 981 BELGIUM LUXEMBOURG Tel.: 0800 49653 (BE) Tel.: 8002 3034 (LUX) BRAZIL Tel.: 0800 7777 747 CHINA Tel.: 108 0065 00515 (N) Tel.: 108 0026 50532 (S) CZECH REPUBLIC Tel.: 0 224 800 184

Nurissa S.A. Tel.: 032 344 88 44 Dallmayr SA Chur Tel.: 081 284 22 48 Dallmayr SA Ticino Tel.: 091 995 15 41 Presto Cafe Services S.A. Tel.: 021 721 52 20 UNITED KINGDOM Tel.: 0808 100 88 44 USA CANADA Tel.: 1 800 566 0571

 ]]></page>
<page num="107"><![CDATA[
COFFEE MARK Markus & Daniel Freitag

 ]]></page>
<page num="108"><![CDATA[
INFORMATION Addresses

CITY GUIDE
ZURICH ZOO Zurichbergstrasse 221, 8044 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 254 25 05 www.zoo.ch CENTRE LE CORBUSIER Höschgasse 8, 8008 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 383 64 70 www.centerlecorbusier.com SCHWARZENBACH Münstergasse 19, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 261 13 15 www.schwarzenbach.ch WALDRAUD Josefstrasse 142, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 554 60 50 www.waldraud.com THEMA SELECTION Spiegelgasse 16, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 261 78 42 www.themaselection.ch JIM GERBER Rämistrasse 29, 8006 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 251 71 24 www.jimgerber.com HYATT Beethovenstrasse 21, 8002 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 883 12 34 www.zurich.park.hyatt.com BÄRENGASSE Bahnhofstrasse 25, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 210 08 08 www.restaurant-baerengasse.ch KUNSTHAUS ZÜRICH Heimplatz 1, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 253 84 84 www.kunsthaus.ch EDITION POPULAIRE Lagerstrasse 93, 8004 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 243 90 92 www.editionpopulaire.ch FREITAG Geroldstrasse 17, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 366 95 20 www.freitag.ch

All the addresses mentioned by Club Members on pages 22 - 39.
DANIEL H Müllerstrasse 51, 8004 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 241 41 78 www.danielh.ch BARFUSSBAR Stadthausquai 12, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 251 33 31 www.barfussbar.ch MARKTHALLE Limmatstrasse 231, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 201 00 60 www.restaurant-markthalle.ch EL LOKAL Gessner-Allee 11, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 344 87 50 www.ellokal.ch SCHOBER Napfgasse 4, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 251 51 50 www.peclard-zurich.ch WIDDER Rennweg 7, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 224 25 26 www.widderhotel.ch ROSSO Geroldstrasse 31, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 818 22 54 www.restaurant-rosso.ch BOGEN 33 Geroldstrasse 33, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 400 00 33 www.bogen33.ch FRAU GEROLDS GARTEN Geroldstrasse 23, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)78 637 00 31 www.geroldgarten.ch CAREDDA Josefstrasse 119, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 440 23 41 www.konditorei-caredda.ch DIDI’S FRIEDEN Stampfenbachstrasse 32, 8006 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 253 18 10 www.didisfrieden.ch BAR RIO Gessnerallee 17, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 244 09 09 www.riozurich.ch KAFI SCHNAPS Kornhausstrasse 57, 8037 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 538 81 16 www.kafischnaps.ch JDABURG Gertrudstrasse 44, 8003 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 451 18 42 www.jdaburg.ch FISHER’S FRITZ Seestrasse 559, 8038 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 480 13 40 www.fischers-fritz.ch LÖWENBRÄU AREAL COMPLEX Limmatstrasse 268, 8005 Zürich TIMES (RESTAURANT) Gasometerstrasse 7, 8005 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 211 99 77 www.times-zurich.com THE RESTAURANT (DOLDER GRAND) Kurhausstrasse 65, 8032 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 456 60 00 www.thedoldergrand.com MESA Weinbergstrasse 75, 8006 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)43 321 75 75 www.mesa-restaurant.ch WIRTSCHAFT ZUM WIESENGRUND Kleindorfstrasse 61, 8707 Uetikon am See ℡ +41 (0)44 920 63 60 www.wiesengrund.ch BAUR AU LAC Talstrasse 1, 8001 Zürich ℡ +41 (0)44 220 50 20 www.bauraulac.ch

STYLE & DESIGN
Find stockists of the brands featured in the following sections:

Style, pp. 46 - 51
VICTORINOX www.victorinox.com/ch CARAN D’ACHE www.carandache.ch SWATCH www.swatch.com LA PRAIRIE www.laprairie.com

Design, pp. 60 - 65
MORITZ SCHMID www.moritz-schmid.com KASPAR MÜLLER www.nicolaskrupp.com/kaspar-müller ALFREDO HÄBERLI www.alfredo-haeberli.com ANA ROLDAN www.anaroldan.ch CARMEN & URS GREUTMANN www.gbdesign.ch KAZU HUGGLER www.kazuhuggler.com MARCUS KRAFT www.marcuskraft.net

 ]]></page>
<page num="109"><![CDATA[
INFORMATION Street Map
MAP from www.mapscd.com ILLUSTRATIONS Matthieu Carré

THE NESPRESSO BOUTIQUES
Find the 2 Zurich Boutiques on the map.
Nespresso Club, Switzerland : freephone 0800 55 52 53 Bleicherweg 5, 8001 Zürich. Löwenstrasse 32, 8001 Zürich.

ZURICH

#19

 ]]></page>
<page num="110"><![CDATA[
FORTISSIO LUNGO & POTATO RÖSTI WITH BOILED EGG AND BACON

ROMA & CENOVIS AND BINDENFLEISCH BITES

ESPRESSO MACCHIATO CAPRICCIO & BIRCHER MUESLI

CAPPUCCINO VOLLUTO & FRENCH TOAST

 ]]></page>
<page num="111"><![CDATA[
ROMA & CENOVIS AND BINDENFLEISCH BITES
SERVES 6 PREPARATION TIME: 30 min RESTING TIME: at least 30 min COOKING TIME: 25 min INGREDIENTS: 6 Roma capsules (6 x 40 ml) For the bites: 500 g (14 oz) flour - 150 ml (5 fl oz) warm semi-

FORTISSIO LUNGO & POTATO RÖSTI WITH BOILED EGG AND BACON
SERVES 6 PREPARATION TIME: 20 min COOKING TIME: 20 min INGREDIENTS: 6 Fortissio Lungo capsules (6 x 110 ml) For the Rösti: 800 g (1lb 12 oz) potatoes - oil - butter -

6 thin-cut slices of bacon - 6 boiled eggs - salt - ground pepper.

skimmed milk at room temperature - 40 g (1 ½ oz) melted butter - 5 g yeast - salt - 50 g (2 oz) bicarbonate of soda Cenovis (or Marmite) - 12 slices of Bindenfleisch - butter to spread. Mix the yeast with the warm milk, pour into a food processor, then add the flour, 150 ml water, butter and 5 g salt. ■ Knead the dough at a low speed until it is consistent and does not stick to the side of the bowl, adding a little flour if necessary. ■ Leave the dough in a warm place to rise for at least 30 minutes. ■ Shape into small oblong rolls. ■ Pre-heat the oven to 200 °C (gas mark 6 - 7), remove the tray from the oven and cover in baking paper. Pour 1 litre of water, the bicarbonate of soda and 4 pinches of salt into a large saucepan. Place two rolls at a time in the boiling water and remove as soon as they rise to the surface. ■ Place the rolls on the tray, cut two diagonal lines on the top, and cook in the oven for 20 to 25 minutes. ■ Leave to cool then halve and butter the rolls. Spread Cenovis (or Marmite) on one half and put the Bindenfleisch on the other. ■ Serve with a Roma. Peel the potatoes, wipe with kitchen roll and grate. ■ Heat a little oil and butter in a non-stick pan. ■ Shape the grated potato into small rounds and fry in the pan over low heat for around 20 minutes, turning regularly until golden. Season to taste. ■ Fry the bacon at the side of the pan or in another pan with a drop of oil. ■ Cook the eggs in boiling water for 3 or 4 minutes. ■ Serve the röstis with the bacon, boiled eggs and toast. ■ Serve with a Fortissio Lungo.

Ritual Espresso cup (Nespresso - design Andrée Putman). Plate (Atelier de Madame M).
Production Marie Leteuré Stylist Élodie Rambaud Photography Jérôme Bilic

Glass Lungo cup (Nespresso).
Production Marie Leteuré Stylist Élodie Rambaud Photography Jérôme Bilic

CAPPUCCINO VOLLUTO & FRENCH TOAST
SERVES 6 PREPARATION TIME: 10 min COOKING TIME: 15 min INGREDIENTS: 6 Volluto capsules (6 x 40 ml) - hot frothed milk. For the French toast: 300 ml (10 ½ fl oz) milk - 3 eggs -

ESPRESSO MACCHIATO CAPRICCIO & BIRCHER MUESLI
SERVES 6 PREPARATION TIME: 20 min COOLING TIME: 4 h INGREDIENTS: 6 Capriccio capsules (6 x 40 ml) -

100 g (4 oz) sugar - 1 teaspoon of cinnamon 6 slices of slightly dry bread - butter for cooking.

2 teaspoons of frothed milk per cup.
For the muesli: 3 apples - 1 banana - 150 g ( 5 oz) porridge oats -

200 ml (7 fl oz) milk - 250 g (9 oz) cream cheese 2 natural yoghurts - 1 lemon - 1 tablespoon of honey 2 or 3 kinds of frozen summer fruits.

Beat the eggs with the sugar and cinnamon. ■ Soak the slices of bread in the warm or hot milk then in the egg mixture and fry on both sides in a pan with butter. ■ Dust with a little sugar just before serving. ■ Serve with a cappuccino made with a Volluto and hot frothed milk.

In a large bowl, pour the milk over the porridge oats. ■ Peel the apples, keep one aside to dice and grate the others into the bowl. ■ Add the lemon juice, cream cheese, yoghurts, honey, diced apple, banana and the summer fruits chopped into small pieces. ■ Mix gently and refrigerate for at least 4 hours. ■ This muesli can be kept for 3 or 4 days in the fridge. ■ Serve with an Espresso Macchiato

prepared with a Capriccio and 2 teaspoons of frothed milk.

Glass Cappuccino cup (Nespresso).
Production Marie Leteuré Stylist Élodie Rambaud Photography Jérôme Bilic

Glass Lungo cup (Nespresso). Bowl (Mud Australia).
Production Marie Leteuré Stylist Élodie Rambaud Photography Jérôme Bilic

 ]]></page>
<page num="112"><![CDATA[
Executive Dual time
Self-winding. Patented time zone quick setting. Black ceramic bezel and 18 ct rose gold case. Water-resistant to 100 m. Rubber band.
W W W . U LY S S E - N A R D I N . C O M For a catalog, call 561 988 8600 email: usa87@ulysse-nardin.com or U LY S S E N A R D I N S A - S w i t z e r l a n d +41 32 930 7400 - email: info@ulysse-nardin.ch

 ]]></page>

</texte>
